Dept idea what the future could look like with Yaoi
部門はやおいの将来がどうなるかを考えています
So she gives da ice´ elevator a nice new way or we could go out to hang out
それで彼女はアイスのエレベーターに素敵な新しい方法を教えてくれた、そうでなければ私たちは遊びに行くこともできる
So
それで
and
と
then
それから
you
あなた
because
なぜなら
free
自由
it
それ
remembrance
記憶
between
間
ah
ああ
distinguished guests
著名なゲスト
Tonight's speech was supposed to be hosted by Vice President Chen Jianren
今夜の演説は陳建仁副総統が司会を務める予定だった
But because Vice President Chen Jianren had to go abroad for work
しかし、陳建仁副総統は仕事で海外に行かなければならなかったので、
so let me represent
だから私が代表させてください
Then the Senate of the Lee Academy was born in 1932
その後、1932 年に李源の上院が誕生しました。
He told me not to talk too much
彼は私にあまり話さないようにと言った
so what about me
それで私はどうですか
I didn't prepare his information first.
私は最初に彼の情報を準備しませんでした。
So let me just say
それで、ちょっと言わせてください
Well because he's very polite
まあ、彼はとても礼儀正しいので
Then he is the 20th academician of our academy
それで彼は私たちのアカデミーの20人目の学者です
Academician Li received his bachelor's and master's degrees from the Department of Agrochemistry, National Taiwan University
李院士は国立台湾大学農芸化学科で学士号と修士号を取得しました。
Then came to the United States in 1958
そして1958年に米国に渡った
University of Elva
エルバ大学
Read in 1960 to get Ph.D. in biochemistry
1960年に生化学の博士号を取得するために読んだ
Professor at Johns Hopkins University
ジョンズ・ホプキンス大学教授
until now
今まで
Then his research field is mainly this
それでは彼の研究分野は主にこれです
In-class research
堂內研究
His research in this hall
このホールでの彼の研究
my limited knowledge
私の限られた知識
Known is a very difficult field
既知は非常に難しい分野です
then he is here
それなら彼はここにいるよ
A very cutting-edge foundation in the field
この分野における最先端の基盤
scientific research
科学研究
Then the hall is one of the main components of the cell
ホールはセルの主要な構成要素の 1 つです
To understand the function of the hall, you must first decipher the structure
ホールの機能を理解するには、まず構造を読み解く必要があります
Over the years, a series of internal quantifications developed by Academician Li
長年にわたり、リー学者によって開発された一連の内部定量化
qualitative analysis
定性分析
Has become a model of micro analysis in the hall
ホール内のミクロ分析のモデルとなっています
Then there is a great achievement in this area
この分野では非常に高い成果が得られています
also won many awards
多くの賞も受賞しました
Then he told me not to talk about it.
それから彼は私にそのことについては話さないように言いました。
so i'm left
だから私は残った
Please refer to yourself
あなた自身を参照してください
In fact it's not just this
実はこれだけじゃないんです
not just this there are many
これだけじゃなくてたくさんあるよ
Well, what he's accomplished in this area is outstanding.
まあ、この分野で彼が成し遂げたことは傑出したものです。
then in education
それから教育の分野で
Research and other contributions are very admirable
研究やその他の貢献は非常に賞賛に値します
Well of course he has an identity
もちろん彼にはアイデンティティがあります
He is Dean Li's brother
彼はディーン・リーの弟です
Well, I think everyone knows this
まあ、これは誰でも知っていると思いますが、
But what is the topic of his speech today?
しかし、今日の彼のスピーチのテーマは何でしょうか？
It's beyond everyone's expectations
それはみんなの予想を超えている
He's talking about the Columbian influence on Taiwanese food
彼は台湾料理に対するコロンビアの影響について話しています。
I saw this topic two days ago
2日前にこのトピックを見ました
Surprised
驚いた
I asked Academician Li, do you really want to talk about this topic?
私はリー学術院議員に、本当にこのテーマについて話したいのですかと尋ねました。
real
本物
so i'm very curious
だからとても興味があります
very curious
非常好奇
Because this seems to have nothing to do with the hall
ホールとは関係なさそうなので
But it seems to be wrong again
でもまた間違ってるようです
We now give warm applause to Mr. Lee Yen Choi
今、リー・イェン・チェ氏に温かい拍手を送ります。
Thank you Wang Guoyuan
王国源さん、ありがとう
Thank you for your help
ご協力ありがとうございました
This is also surprising
これもびっくりですよ
Usually, this kind of speech is an expert's speech.
通常、この種のスピーチは専門家のスピーチです。
A less specialized way of talking about specialized things
専門的ではない、専門的な事柄について話す方法
what about me
私はどうなの
Is to talk about the influence of public forces Taiwanese food
公軍の影響を語る台湾料理
then you can ask
それから尋ねることができます
What qualifications do I have to say this?
これを言うには何の資格が必要ですか？
i am not a historian
私は歴史家ではありません
not a sociologist
社会学者ではありません
not a linguist
言語学者ではありません
But what?
でも何？
The Duoduo sofa we make biochemical has something to do with food
私たちが生化学的に作った Duoduo ソファは食品と関係があります
I've also led for several years on food-related panels in the U.S.
私はまた、米国の食品関連のパネルでも数年間主導してきました。
then you can tell
そうすれば言えるよ
Our lab also prints six or seven lessons of this cookbook
私たちの研究室では、このクックブックの 6 つまたは 7 つのレッスンも印刷しています
I think such words from netizens
ネット民からはこんな言葉があったと思う
Is it enough to talk about this topic?
このトピックについて話すだけで十分ですか?
enough enough
十分に十分
then it can be done
それならできるよ
then the world is so big
そうすれば世界はとても広いです
Well, 26 of these major crops in the world
さて、世界の主要作物のうち 26 品目
Eight of these are from the so-called New World
そのうち 8 つはいわゆる新世界から来たものです
Then these 8 are the Malin tree fan tree
では、この8本がマリンツリーファンツリーです
Cornwood Tree Tomato Chili
コーンウッド ツリー トマト チリ
happening chocolate and vanilla
チョコレートとバニラが起こる
I'll talk about every
それぞれについて話します
After this bug every
このバグの後、
Plus a lot more
さらに、さらに多くのこと
so i now explain
だから私は今説明します
This screen we are talking about
私たちが話しているこの画面
mostly in Chinese
ほとんど中国語で
Alto Control
アルトコントロール
also only in english
それも英語のみで
But English is very simple
でも英語はとても簡単です
So I hope you can understand
ですから、ご理解いただけると幸いです
I left English on purpose
わざと英語から離れた
Then in this bug
それからこのバグでは
Seven of them are made in Taiwan
そのうち7つは台湾製です
So start with this
だからこれから始めてください
Dried sweet potatoes and sweet potatoes
干し芋・さつまいも
Sweet potatoes are often used in Taiwan
台湾ではサツマイモがよく使われます
to describe its own
それ自体を説明する
Then if you turn around late at night
それで夜遅くに振り向いたら
you can see a lot
たくさん見ることができます
Seven hundred are all about sweet potatoes and dried potatoes
セブンハンドレッドといえばサツマイモと干し芋ばかり
sweet potato thing
サツマイモの事
So
それで
this is my name
これが私の名前です
panzi food sweet potato tomato blah blah blah
パンジー 食べ物 サツマイモ トマト 何とか何とか何とか
This is actually not too strange
これは実際にはそれほど奇妙ではありません
because you are watching
あなたが見ているから
You also read the previous things
以前のものも読みました
zucchini pepper a lot of stuff
ズッキーニピーマンたっぷり
Most of this nonsense is pointing
このナンセンスのほとんどは指摘している
Something from the West or the North Food
西または北の食べ物
So what about Fanzi? This is Fanzi's.
では、Fanzi はどうでしょうか? これは Fanzi のものです。
And the food, mostly from the new road
そして食べ物、ほとんどが新しい道路からのもの
So you just watch Fanzi
だから、Panziを見てください。
where the hell did the old one come from
古いものは一体どこから来たのですか
What about a lot of this food? Its name is
この食べ物がたくさんあるのはどうでしょうか?その名前は
with this history
この歴史とともに
factor there
そこに要因がある
then let's talk
それから話しましょう
Gansu liquid melon
甘粛液状メロン
What about this, of course, in Latin?
もちろん、これをラテン語ではどうでしょうか？
Don't touch it, Watatas
触らないでください、ワタタス
five thousand years ago
五千年前
Believe in what you say
あなたの言うことを信じてください
human begins
人間が始まる
start planting start improving
植え付けを開始し、改良を開始
Then theirs were planted 5,000 years ago
彼らのものは5,000年前に植えられたものです
not what we see now
私たちが今見ているものではありません
So 5,000 years ago it was many of these farmers and so on
つまり、5,000年前には、これらの農民の多くがそうでした。
Both improved very differently
どちらも改善方法は大きく異なりました
So don't think that five thousand years will be so good
だから、五千年がそれほど良いものになるとは思わないでください
where is the sweet potato
サツマイモはどこですか
Sorry this point can only
申し訳ありませんが、この点はのみ可能です
Can only be used in the middle of this
この途中でのみ使用できます
Then both sides can not see
そうなると両側が見えなくなります
But you can do this progressive movement to the left and right
しかし、この段階的な動きを左右に行うことはできます。
then you can also see
それならあなたも見ることができます
This one looks like the millennium flower, right?
これはミレニアムフラワーに似ていますね？
In fact, this is the subject of the same genus
実際、これは同じ属の主題です
Then I will talk about the innermost thing later.
では、一番奥のことについては後ほどお話します。
There were many, many
たくさんありました、たくさんありました
So
それで
Let me tell you, there is no need to talk about this, sweet potatoes can also be boiled, baked, and many things can be cooked
言っておきますが、これについて話す必要はありません、サツマイモは煮たり焼いたり、いろいろな料理ができます。
Honey sweet potato will be discussed in more detail later
はちみつ芋については後ほど詳しく説明します
One advantage is that the sweet potato experience can also be eaten
スイートポテト体験も食べられるのが利点
I just ate this even if I didn’t speak Chinese
中国語が話せなくてもこれだけ食べました
How did sweet potatoes come to Taiwan?
サツマイモはどのようにして台湾に伝わったのでしょうか？
there are many stories
たくさんの話があります
What I want to introduce to you now is the honey sweet potato cultural system
今回ご紹介したいのは、はちみつ芋の栽培システムです。
This is quoted in this book
この本の中で引用されています
Spanish sailors first brought this dried potato to the Philippines
スペインの船員がこの乾燥ジャガイモを初めてフィリピンに持ち込んだ
Do you remember that the Philippines was controlled by Spain for a while
フィリピンがしばらくスペインに支配されていたことを覚えていますか
So of course the Spaniards can bring this thing to the Philippines
もちろん、スペイン人はこれをフィリピンに持ち込むことができます
The Philippines can be considered part of the country of Spain
フィリピンはスペインの一部と考えることができます
It is strictly prohibited to export and cannot be exported
輸出は固く禁止されており、輸出することはできません
However, what is forbidden
ただし、禁止されていることは
Everyone knows how Yan Duoduo has a way
ヤン・ドゥオドゥオのやり方は誰もが知っています
move out, can do that
出て行け、出てもいいよ
Not only the Chinese, other countries will be like this
中国人に限らず他の国もそうなるだろう
Hu Jianren and Chen Yi introduced China from the Philippines
胡建仁と陳毅がフィリピンから中国を紹介
It's just a sneak attack
奇襲攻撃だよ
Exactly a few years later, in 1993, Hu Jian had a violent attack
ちょうど数年後の1993年、胡建は暴力的な暴行を受けた。
Hu Jian already had a lot of aggressive defenses
胡建はすでに多くの攻撃的な守備を持っていた
Hell is not good and the weather is not good
地獄は良くないし、天気も良くない
So this year, Chen Yi's son
それで今年、チェンイーの息子は
The students at that time called him to grow sweet potatoes
当時の生徒たちからサツマイモ作りに誘われた
to improve blood volume
血液量を改善するために
Then, there is another post, Chen Yi posted in Dong Huan
それから、別の投稿があります、Chen Yi が東環に投稿しました
In 1963, he talked about the aboriginal farming in Gansu
1963年、彼は甘粛省の先住民農業について語った。
Spaniards once also came to the northern part of Taiwan
かつてスペイン人も台湾北部にやって来た
At that time, it may also bring Gansu
その時、甘粛も連れてくるかもしれない
Then there is also evidence that redhead fish and Taitung are growing in Gansu
次に、甘粛省で赤毛の魚と台東が成長しているという証拠があります
This was discovered by the South China people
これは中国南部の人々によって発見されました
Of course, it is very likely that it emerged from the other side.
もちろん、向こう側から現れた可能性が非常に高いです。
Well, especially if you've heard
まあ、特に聞いたことがあるなら
When Zheng Chenggong first arrived in Taiwan
鄭成功が初めて台湾に到着したとき
he wasn't prepared
彼は準備ができていなかった
That is to say, he did not prepare the food for his 30,000 people
つまり、彼は3万人の人々に食事を用意しなかったのです。
Fortunately, Taiwan has been able to grow Gansu
幸いなことに、台湾は甘粛省を成長させることができました。
According to the Spanish cultural system
スペインの文化体系によると
They can plant Gansu for two months
甘粛省は2ヶ月間植えることができる
three month army
3ヶ月の軍隊
so pretty good
とても良い
So why are sweet potatoes sweet?
では、なぜサツマイモは甘いのでしょうか？
Take a few people. Small sweet potatoes are sweet
数人でどうぞ小さなサツマイモは甘いです
Not very
あまり
It is directly influenced by the fact that sweet potatoes are sweet
サツマイモが甘いという事実が直接影響している
why is it sweet
なぜ甘いのですか
Because it has a little more length
長くてもっとだから
a little more than this usual sheep feather
通常の羊の羽より少し多い
But this one is only a small part
しかし、これはほんの一部に過ぎません
Then the sweet potato contains electricity to remove catabolites
サツマイモには異化産物を除去する電気が含まれています
So it can decompose the electricity in the sweet potato
サツマイモの電気を分解できるので
So if you are interested in making a comparison
したがって、比較に興味がある場合は、
If you bake the sweet potatoes in a resistance oven, they won't be sweet
サツマイモを抵抗オーブンで焼くと甘くなりません
not too sweet
甘すぎない
So if you are afraid of sweets, I think few people are afraid of sweets
だから甘いものが怖いなら、甘いものを怖がる人はほとんどいないと思います
If so, you can use a resistance grill to bake it.
その場合は、抵抗グリルを使用して焼くこともできます。
As long as you go with a normal oven
普通のオーブンで焼く限り
Just dry and crispy but very sweet
乾燥していてサクサクしていますが、とても甘いです
feel very sweet
とても甘く感じる
There was a candied radish just now.
さっき大根の甘露煮がありました。
put a handful of dried crisps in
乾燥したポテトチップスを一掴み入れます
If you boil it slowly in a normal pot
普通の鍋でじっくり煮ると
becomes very very sweet
とてもとても甘くなります
Everyone, I think anyone who has a commemoration of his release knows this.
皆さん、彼の釈放を記念する人なら誰でも知っていると思います。
So what is the nutrition of sweet potato
では、さつまいもにはどのような栄養があるのでしょうか？
The biggest feature is that it has vitamin A very very high
最大の特徴はビタミンAが非常に豊富に含まれていることです。
This is 262% of Rixu, which is three times
これはリクシューの262%で3倍です。
just too much
多すぎる
not too much
多すぎない程度に
very many
非常に多くの
This one is better than this Potato than sheep feather
羊の羽よりもこのジャガイモよりもこちらの方がいい
Others of course there are many of this
もちろん他にもたくさんあります
so-called micronutrients
いわゆる微量栄養素
is very important one has
それは非常に重要です
Then if we talk about heat
では、熱について言えば、
Sweets and vegetables are not too high
お菓子も野菜も高すぎない
Even with this daily allowance, it’s not too high
この日当でも高すぎるわけではない
So
それで
What is the production volume of Fangen
ファンゲンの生産量はどれくらいですか
if use this
これを使えば
The average beauty is the average
平均的な美しさは平均的です
In terms of production volume
生産量で見ると
yes
はい
Papua New Guinea
パプアニューギニア
is the highest
最高です
Solomon D'Or
ソロモンドール
big bed is
大きなベッドは
one hundred sixty seven four
一百六十七四
you can tell
教えてもいいよ
No matter what you play, rodless
何を弾いてもロッドレス
are higher
高いです
not in
ありませんで
beautiful countries
美しい国
So it can be seen that this is already
したがって、これはすでに
new big thing
新しい大きなこと
Useful elsewhere
他の場所でも役立つ
So
それで
Of course you can also see
もちろん見ることもできます
these things are
これらのことは
Can't grow rice
米が育てられない
A place where wheat cannot be grown
小麦が作れない場所
So
それで
now for this
今はこれのために
Potatoes
ポテト
This Qinghua must be earlier
この清華はもっと早いはずです
Evidence from 10,000 years ago
1万年前の証拠
People's species
人々の種族
Of course not a smaller one like this
もちろんこれほど小さいものではありません
I haven't seen it either
私も見たことがありません
In 10,000 years, the future is not here
1万年後の未来はここには無い
But according to archaeologists
しかし考古学者によれば、
not that big
そんなに大きくない
The Poleto Solanum Tuvarossum
ポレトナス トゥヴァロッサム
The languages ​​spoken are very different
話されている言語は大きく異なります
Spanish speaks Pata
スペイン語を話すパタ
It comes from this native language
この母国語から来ています
another kind of speech
別の種類のスピーチ
Like this Art Appel in Dutch
オランダ語でこのアートアピールのように
It's an earthy apple
素朴なリンゴです
Another kind of speech is Italian Russian
別の種類のスピーチはイタリア語、ロシア語です
Shoes
靴
This is the very expensive shiitake mushroom from France.
フランス産の非常に高価な椎茸です。
what is shiitake
しいたけの名前は何ですか
I forgot
忘れてた
but anyway
とにかく
That's it
それでおしまい
This Italian uses this
このイタリア人はこれを使っています
The Germans are changing it a bit, called Karatover
ドイツ人はそれを少し変えています、Karatoverと呼ばれます
Germans also use art apple, art is to the apple
ドイツ人もアートアップルを使う、アートはリンゴにある
Russia also uses this Karatover
ロシアもこのカラトーバーを使用しています
French is the same as the local Marlins, potatoes are the same as the Continental
フレンチは地元のマーリンズと同じ、ポテトはコンチネンタルと同じです。
In Ruiyu is Marlins, and Gagaimo
るいゆにはマーリンズ、ガガイモ
Gagimo is when they brought in
ガギモは彼らが持ち込んだときのものです
It's Gabba from Sofa, which was called Gagarda back then
当時ガガルダと呼ばれていたソファのガバです。
so it's called gageimo
だからガガイモって言うんです
This Puttlang is also like the French style
このプットランもフランス風ですね
It is rented by the old party, and its scope is wider
旧党が借りているので範囲が広い
To remember this soldier and this generation
この兵士とこの世代を思い出すために
wars among european countries wars other than climate
ヨーロッパ諸国間の戦争 気候変動以外の戦争
So get big
だから大きくなってね
However, most of these countries can still grow wheat
しかし、これらの国々のほとんどは依然として小麦を栽培することができます。
Therefore, it is not necessary to rely entirely on this Potato for rescue.
したがって、救助をこのポテトに全面的に依存する必要はありません。
So they are more manageable
したがって、より管理しやすくなります
But Alan
でもアラン
Ailan is the most popular snack for Potato
愛蘭はポテトの最も人気のあるスナックです
There is a good reason for this
これには十分な理由があります
makes sense
意味がある
We have been to Ireland twice
私たちはアイルランドに2回行ったことがあります
Then I learned a lot about the history and geography of Ailan
それから愛蘭の歴史と地理についてたくさん学びました
The geography of Ailan is
愛蘭の地理は、
It was hundreds of years ago
何百年も前のことだ
Ailan mainly develops here
Ailanは主にここで開発されています
This area is better
この辺のほうがいいよ
All kinds of things grow faster
あらゆる種類のものの成長が速くなります
but later
でもその後
british light loveland after
ブリティッシュ・ライト・ラブランド・アフター
take the original geography
元の地理を取得する
The man who loves blue comes here
青を愛する男がここに来る
Here is the land is very bad
ここは土地が非常に悪いところです
You can tell from this
このことからわかります
This is also the image I made last year
こちらも去年作った画像です
is very convenient
とても便利です
many stones
たくさんの石
nothing looks right
何も正しく見えません
Only potatoes can
只有Potato才能
In order to grow up in this kind of place
こんなところで育つために
so what
だから何
Originally the basic thing of the Inca Empire was Potato
もともとインカ帝国の基本はジャガイモでした
And after it spread to Europe in 1570
そして1570年にヨーロッパに広まった後
Ailan is the first to collect money on a large scale
アイランは初めて大規模な資金を集めた
late 16th century
16世紀末
big success
栽培大成功
Not very successful
あまり成功していない
Now they don't have anything to eat
今、彼らには食べるものが何もありません
so what
だから何
they succeeded
彼らは成功した
Able to export to European countries
ヨーロッパ諸国への輸出が可能
So the personality is super positive all at once
なので性格は一気に超ポジティブです
this
これ
these decades
この数十年
Just from five a day
1日5個からだけ
million to eight million
100万から800万まで
increase very quickly
非常に早く増加します
The increase is fast, of course there is something wrong
増加が早い、もちろん何か問題がある
so why is there a problem
それでなぜ問題があるのですか
Because other crops cannot grow
他の作物が育たないので
only grow potatoes
ジャガイモだけを育てる
Then it becomes monocrop
そうするとモノクロになります
Single crop problems are many
単一作物の問題は数多くある
Because disease is easy to come
病気になりやすいので
So get this kind of here is an example
このようなものを取得します。ここに例があります
black spot
黒点
The disease of potatoes
ジャガイモの病気
This disease still exists
この病気はまだ存在します
not completely wiped out
完全には払拭されていない
But then it was the most powerful
でも当時はそれが一番強かった
Then what
じゃあ何
After finding the disease
病気が見つかってから
Then most of the potatoes just fell off.
するとジャガイモのほとんどが落ちてしまいました。
So make this big famine in Aran
だからアランでこの大飢饉を起こしてください
Then what
じゃあ何
It can be seen that this very, very powerful hope
この非常に強力な希望が
Therefore, the population will decrease greatly after this place exists.
したがって、この場所が存在した後、人口は大幅に減少します。
From this number reduced like this
この数字からこのように減りました
It is one of the four languages ​​of Taiwan
台湾の4つの言語のうちの1つです
some are immigrants
移民もいる
some are dead
何人かは死んでいる
So this has a great influence on Ailan
これはアイランに大きな影響を与えます
And the result of immigration
そして移民の結果
It also means that at least two presidents of the United States are pure Irish
それはまた、米国の少なくとも2人の大統領が純粋なアイルランド人であることを意味する
Well, Obama now also says he is one of the eight writers
さて、オバマも今では自分が8人の作家のうちの1人であると言っています
Or one of the few texts is the Irishman
あるいは、数少ないテキストの 1 つがアイルランド人です。
No matter how many who is one of the few texts
たとえ誰が数少ないテキストの一人であっても
Anyway, this is a big problem
とにかく、これは大問題です
how to solve this problem
この問題をどうやって解決するか
Later, it was more disease-resistant and disease-resistant from the United States.
その後、アメリカからより耐病性が高くなっていきました。
Insect-resistant species reintroduction
害虫耐性のある種の再導入
Only input can solve this problem
この問題はインプットだけで解決できる
It turns out that Mallinson's origin is in
マリンソンの起源は
Biru is about the middle of Bolivia
ビルはボリビアのほぼ中央にあります
this is very famous
これはとても有名です
Lake Titicaca
チチカカ湖
what about this lake
この湖はどうですか
So it's interesting to say
だからこう言うのは面白い
the people who live in this lake
この湖に住む人々
don't live on land
陸に住んではいけません
They took this little grass that grows in the water
彼らは水の中に生えるこの小さな草を採取しました
How many percent is one meter two meters thick
1メートル2メートルの厚さは何パーセントですか
Then build a house on it and do all kinds of stuff
そして、その上に家を建てて、いろいろなことをしてみましょう
If the children grow up and want to separate
子どもたちが成長して別れたいと思ったら
It's the turf not the soil
それは土ではなく芝生です
sod cut
芝刈り
It's a separation
別居だよ
formal separation
正式分家
what about this
これはどうですか
just about
ほぼ
The origin of this potato
このジャガイモの由来
So
それで
A few years ago we went to Match of Pitch
数年前、私たちはマッチ・オブ・ピッチに行きました
this is very nice
これはすごく素敵
It is said that in these places
こういった場所ではそう言われています
Counted more than 2000 people
数えたら2000人以上
What do they say is Potato
彼らはジャガイモとは何と言いますか
Mainly Potato
主にジャガイモ
Where is the potato planted?
ジャガイモはどこに植えられていますか？
planted here
ここに植えられた
I didn't find anything
何かが見つかりませんでした
But the area here is not too big
でもここのエリアはそんなに広くない
But it can support 2000 people
しかし、2000人をサポートできる
is quite productive quite high
かなり生産性が高い
Then learn this little biology
それから、この小さな生物学を学びましょう
say something
何か言って
place of origin
原産地
on average a lot
平均してたくさん
average less words
平均して単語が少ない
For example, the European race
例えばヨーロッパの人種
Yes, there are fewer types
はい、種類が少ないです
Africa is more
アフリカはもっとある
Because Africa is native
アフリカ原産だから
Potato, Patata, Patata
那麼Potato, Patata, Patata
this can sometimes be confusing
これは時々混乱を招く可能性があります
For example, in the early
たとえば、初期の頃、
spanish
スペイン語
or italian
またはイタリア語
I often confuse Potato with sheep feathers
私はよくジャガイモと羊の羽を混同します
But in Cretia are these people
でもクレティアにはこんな人たちがいる
These people in Mordaishu right here in England
ここイギリスのモーダイシュにいる人々
Their language is called Cretia
彼らの言語はクレティアと呼ばれます
It translates sweet potato as
サツマイモを訳すと、
Bada in Taiwanese
台湾語で「バダ」
Potato called Bada
バダというジャガイモ
So the Spaniards confuse the two powders
したがって、スペイン人は2つの粉末を混同します
Potato
就Potato
So early records
とても初期の記録
You have to be careful
あなたは注意する必要があります
Sometimes they speak Potato
時々彼らはポテトを話します
But honestly Sweet Potato
でも正直スイートポテト
There is also the progress of the above
上記の進捗状況もあります
So
それで
How should Potato be pronounced?
Potato はどのように発音すればよいでしょうか?
what about this
これはどうですか
I want everyone to listen
みんなに聞いてほしい
Tomato, let's call the old thing off.
トマト、古いことはやめましょう。
I just heard that the famous Armstrong and Inia Fitzgerald
有名なアームストロングとイニア・フィッツジェラルドがいたと聞いたところです
so this is very interesting
これはとても興味深いですね
So it should be Potato, Patata, nothing.
つまり、ポテト、パタタ、何もないはずです。
Let’s talk about Potato production
ジャガイモの生産について話しましょう
If we talk about medium output, it is usually China
中産出量といえば、通常は中国です
But India and the Soviet Union are pretty good
しかし、インドとソ連はかなり良いです
you'll see later
後でわかります
If we look at it per capita, it is not China
一人当たりで見れば中国ではない
Beyer, Indian Kiss, Russia, Baspeia, Poland, Russia, etc.
はい、バイエル、インディアン・キス、ロシア、バスペイア、ポーランド、ロシアなど。
Such as Bolivia, Mexico, and France
ボリビア、メキシコ、フランスなど
very funny
非常に面白い
but anyway
とにかく
It can be seen that these countries can accept new crops from the New World
これらの国は新世界から新しい作物を受け入れることができることがわかります。
Taiwan too
台湾も
Look at Yin Yang again
もう一度陰陽を見てください
do i want to talk
話したいですか
because everyone knows
誰もが知っているから
Anyway, Poleto is quite silver value
とにかくポレートはかなりのシルバー価値があります
is quite high
かなり高いです
Especially the protein is a little higher than this meal
特にたんぱく質は食事数より少し多めに
There are also various hygienic
衛生面でも色々あります
Except Sanitin A
サニチ​​ンAを除く
Everything else is pretty good
他はすべてかなり良いです
words in america
アメリカの言葉
Often eat baked merry meringue
焼きメリーメレンゲをよく食べる
The skin is actually delicious
やっぱり皮が美味しい
Its silver price is compared with the whole Poleto
ポレート全体と比較した銀の価格
is also uncomfortable
も不快です
the good thing is
良いことは
It's just that the skin is worth more
ただ、皮にはもっと価値がある
This is pretty good in terms of real nutrition
これは実際の栄養という点ではかなり優れています
and delicious
そしておいしい
have a big problem
大きな問題がある
that is to say, what I just said
つまり、今私が言ったこと
we may not have talked
私たちは話さなかったかもしれない
Grape fruit can be produced for a long time
グレープフルーツは長期生産可能
several months
好幾個月
sometimes you see it sprout
時々芽が出ているのが見られます
If it sprouts, it's best to throw it away
芽が出たら捨てたほうがいいですよ
Because after germination, there is this
発芽後はこうなるから
Solan Lin
ソラン・リン
nongine
ノンジン
it's poisonous
それは有毒です
So in the past, grapes were more expensive
つまり昔はブドウの方が高価だった
you just cut it off
あなたはそれを切り落としました
but still not sure
しかしまだわかりません
so grape fruit is very cheap now
グレープフルーツは今とても安いです
so you can farm
それで農業ができるように
Don't go for surgery again
二度と手術には行かないでください
then the question
それから質問
I'm not a doctor either
私も医者ではありません
But that's a lot of problems
しかし、それは多くの問題です
If the method of serious illness will be lost
重病の治療法が失われるなら
So this is a big disadvantage
つまりこれは大きなデメリットなのです
So what about the aborigines?
では、先住民族はどうなのでしょうか？
How to deal with marinsu for storage
まりんすを保管する場合の対処法
It has a thing called Tunno
トゥンノというものがあります
this thing is wonderful
これは素晴らしいです
Because Potato is mainly in
ジャガイモが主に入っているので、
place of the anders plateau
アンダース高原の場所
it is very hot during the day
日中はとても暑いです
it's cold at night
夜は寒いです
So put the potato out
だからジャガイモを出して
freeze it
凍らせる
Then step on it during the day
それから日中それを踏んでください
just roll out the water
水を転がすだけです
If you do this kind of work for two or three days
こういう作業を２日、３日続ければ
Become a Tunno
タンノになる
This is this small piece of Potato that was originally a relatively large piece
これは、元々は比較的大きなポテトだった小さな部分です。
After doing this, it is a natural biscuit
こうすることでナチュラルビスケットの出来上がりです
later can
後でできます
It is said that the two or three years of early spring collection
2、3年の早春コレクションと言われています。
And after soaking in water
そして水に浸した後
still quite tasty
まだかなりおいしい
I haven't been out, I've seen
出てないけど見たことある
So if sweet vegetables are compared with potatoes
甘い野菜をジャガイモに例えるなら
Everyone knows this
これは誰もが知っています
Sweets and vegetables prefer to be wet
お菓子や野菜は濡れた状態を好みます
clear weather
晴れ
not potatoes
ジャガイモではありません
As long as it contains energy
エネルギーが含まれている限り
then just saw
それからちょうど見た
Ye Qing can
イェ・チンはできる
I also saw that the leaf buds are poisonous
葉芽には毒があることも分かりました
Sweets and Vegetables Compared to Potatoes
お菓子と野菜をジャガイモにたとえる
It's just Jiuchun
ただのジウチュンだよ
this can last a long time
これは長く続く可能性があります
It's fine for a few months
数ヶ月なら大丈夫
inverse value method
逆数値法
Sweets and Vegetables are Nakato
お菓子と野菜はナカト
I've hit it several times
何回か当たったんですが
When i was young
私がまだ若い時
This is Nakato faster
これは中藤のほうが速い
Sweets and vegetables are not less
お菓子や野菜も少なくありません
Because it crawls on the ground very quickly
地面を這うのがとても早いので
so can't let
だから許せない
This weed grows out
この雑草は生えてきます
Malinsu needs Ecstasy longifolia
マリンスにはエクスタシー プラエコックスが必要です
I have already said that Vitamin A is higher
ビタミンAが高いことはすでに述べました
so often
しばしば
Crop efficiency is compared in terms of heat
作物の効率を熱量で比較
So the sweet potato marinsu just mentioned
で、先ほどのさつまいもまりんす。
We didn't even talk about rice taro
米芋の話もしてなかった
This is not from the Protestants
これはプロテスタントからのものではありません
neither taro nor pony
タロイモでもポニーでもない
but do this
でもこれをしてください
Just watch this first
まずはこれを見てください
This statistic averages eight years
この統計は平均して 8 年です
Statistics made by Japanese agricultural students
日本の農学生が作成した統計
what about sweet potatoes
サツマイモはどうですか
The heat generated by ten projects is so much
10のプロジェクトが生み出す熱量は膨大だ
What about Malinsu?
マリンスはどうですか？
A bit lower but pretty good
少し低いですがかなり良いです
So it's lower
だからもっと低いんだよ
but to understand
しかし、理解するには
Rice planting in Japan can only be done for one period
日本の田植えは一期しかできない
In Taiwan, there are two phases and three phases
台湾では二段階と三段階がある
It should be a little more than this
これよりもう少し多いはずです
But anyway, this sweet potato
それにしても、このサツマイモ
When this caloric standpoint
このカロリーの観点から見ると、
It is the most efficient of this crop
この作物の中で最も効率が良い
Wheat is better than this universe
小麦はこの宇宙よりも優れている
Now let's talk about this corn
さて、このトウモロコシについて話しましょう
Pan wheat
パン小麦
In the United States, English is often spoken in Korn
米国ではコーン語で英語がよく話されます
Korn isn't actually a good name for this corn
実はコーンというのはこのトウモロコシの良い名前ではありません
Korn originally means small particles in English
Kornはもともと英語で小さな粒子を意味します
so what
だから何
Is it right that this corn is called Korn
このトウモロコシをコーンと呼ぶのは正しいですか?
in other countries
他の国で
It's the same English-speaking British word.
これは同じイギリス英語圏の言葉です。
They use Maze
彼らは迷路を使用します
This is from the scientific name
これは学名から
The scientific name also comes from here
学名もここから来ています
So Zia Maze
所以Zia Maze
This corn was also fumigated many years ago
このトウモロコシも何年も前に燻蒸されたものです
So now you can see many kinds of
これで、たくさんの種類が見られるようになりました
Three or four years ago when I went
3、4年前に行ったときは
The ones they most often come up with are shorter
彼らが最も頻繁に思いつくのは短いものです
Not enough corn with large grains
粒の大きなトウモロコシが足りない
came out very tasty
とても美味しかったです
So now that's a lot
それで今ではたくさんです
But also see many kinds of
でも、いろんな種類も見ました
there is a disadvantage
デメリットがあります
because there is a shortcoming
欠点があるから
is it missing something
何かが足りないのですか
The first one is Vitamin B3
まずはビタミンB3です
This is called Ni-Syn
これはNi-Synと呼ばれます
No-Syn
ノーシン
this thing should be
これはそうあるべきだ
Use alkaline water to get the oil out
油分を落とすにはアルカリ水を使用する必要があります
without this
これがなければ
This Pelagra can happen again
このペラグラはまた起こる可能性がある
this is lack
これは不足です
That is, weight loss and physical strength will decrease
つまり、体重が減り、体力が低下してしまうのです。
In addition, cut less chestnut acid and sian acid in the corn
さらに、トウモロコシに含まれる栗酸とシアン酸をカット
this is very important
これはとても重要です
But fortunately, you can supplement these two amino acids by eating beans
しかし幸いなことに、豆を食べることでこれら 2 つのアミノ酸を補うことができます。
Finally, we will talk about beans from the New World.
最後に、新世界の豆についてお話します。
like going to a mexican restaurant
メキシコ料理レストランに行くような
You often see beans come out with corn
トウモロコシと一緒に豆が出てくるのをよく見かけます
all make sense
すべて意味がある
We talked about the word waxy
ワックスという言葉について話しました
Everyone likes glutinous rice, and also likes brown rice
みんなもち米も好き、玄米も好き
So, does glutinous rice have glutinous rice?
では、もち米にはもち米があるのでしょうか？
yes, where
はい、どこで
There was once a time when Nuo corn was discovered in mainland China
かつてヌオコーンが中国本土で発見された時代があった
So China's Scientology is very happy
だから中国のサイエントロジーはとても幸せだ
we also have the origin of corn
トウモロコシの原産地もあります
But then I realized it wasn't
しかし、その後、そうではないことに気づきました
But let's talk about Nomi Chaomi first
まずはノミ・チャオミについて話しましょう
I'll tell you a little deeper knowledge
もう少し深い知識を教えます
This is the test of knowledge
これは知識のテストです
So you should try this
だからこれを試してみるべきです
some people
人によっては
I should talk about this first
まずこのことについて話すべきです
There are many experts here
ここには専門家がたくさんいます
I'm really taking the liberty to say these things
私は本当にこれらのことを自由に言ってます
But I'm more of an expert on this
しかし、私はこれについては専門家です
So obsessive electric mixer is like this
ということで、こだわりの電動ミキサーはこんな感じ
This is called Amylose Amylopectin like this
これをアミロースアミロペクチンといいます。
then the year does matter
それなら年が重要だ
It's probably conceivable
それはおそらく考えられる
it is very sticky
とても粘着性があります
It's not sticky and simple
ベタつかずシンプルです
Therefore, there are fewer obsessive electric lines in glutinous rice
したがって、もち米には強迫的な電気線が少なくなります。
Aminopectin
アミノペクチン
There are many, many electric lines of obsession
強迫観念の電気線は本当にたくさんあります
so normal this
とても普通です
It is usually in the case of brown rice
通常玄米の場合です
mostly
多くの場合
Most of them are electric lines of obsession
それらのほとんどは強迫観念の電気線です
Then the electric lines of obsession are less
そうすれば、執着の電気線は少なくなります
The glutinous rice just mentioned is now
先ほどのもち米は今です。
Although originally discovered in China
元々は中国で発見されたものの、
but already
しかし、すでに
Glutinous rice goes to America
もち米はアメリカへ
Now almost the world's
今ではほぼ世界一です
The so-called glutinous rice electric pattern is
いわゆるもち米電パターンは
so-called glutinous rice
いわゆるもち米
Well this has been said and dance
まあ、これは言われて踊ってください
by the way
ところで
Let me tell you about the glycemic index
グリセミックインデックスについて教えてください
You can't talk about calories in food
食べ物のカロリーについて語ることはできない
It also depends on how the heat is absorbed by ourselves
それは私たち自身が熱をどのように吸収するかにも依存します
some
いくつかの
our reason
私たちの理由
blood sugar rises rapidly
血糖値が急激に上昇する
speak slowly
ゆっくり話す
some
いくつかの
just increase slowly
ゆっくり増やすだけ
And you can't use this weight to calculate
そして、この重みを計算に使用することはできません
So you should use this glycemic index to see
したがって、この血糖指数を使用して確認する必要があります
Well of course I won't go into details
まあ、もちろん詳細には触れません
but
しかし
White rice and grass rice
白米と草米
You can see it by comparing
比べてみればわかります
some things are the same
いくつかのことは同じです
total calories are the same
総カロリーは同じ
The glycemic index is so different
血糖指数が違いすぎる
so what
だから何
The tallest is French bread
一番高いのはフランスパン
Baguette is the highest
バゲットが一番高い
So people who like to eat French bread be careful
なのでフランスパンが好きな人は注意してください
I won’t talk about it, I don’t want to talk about it, you read a lot of such records on the Internet
それについては話さない、話したくない、あなたはインターネットでそのような記録をたくさん読んでいます
Then the third thing I want to talk about is the so-called Banyok
次に、3番目に話したいのは、いわゆるバニョクについてです。
Banyok is probably Cassava in Taiwan.
バニョクはおそらく台湾のキャッサバです。
Yoga, or yoga is the same
ヨガ、あるいはヨガも同じ
Cassava is 木薯、樹薯
キャッサバは木薯、樹薯です
Our common ones are potato flour or Taipei flour.
一般的なものはジャガイモ粉または台北粉です。
In fact, the glutinous rice just mentioned is often mixed to make Taipei flour.
実際、先ほどのもち米を混ぜて台北粉を作ることもよくあります。
But because it becomes very sticky after heating it up a little
ただ、少し加熱するとベタベタしてしまうので、
this is taipei powder
これは台北パウダーです
So the glutinous rice just mentioned is also Taipei flour.
つまり、先ほどのもち米も台北粉です。
It is also the third largest crop in the world
世界で3番目に多い作物でもあります
Mainly not in the US
主にアメリカではない
and mainly in Africa
そして主にアフリカで
Tapioca that can be mainly seen now
今主に見られるタピオカ
There is a spherical Tapioca
球状のタピオカが入っています
Making Tapioca Balls
做球状的Tapioca
i don't have time to talk
話す時間がない
what to say later
後で何を言うか
wait a minute i will talk too
ちょっと待ってください、私も話します
Also by Tapioca
こちらもタピオカ
There is also Tapioca made into balls
ボール状にしたタピオカもあります
I have already mentioned
すでに述べました
Counting Electric Soul
カウンティング・エレクトリック・ソウル
The quality electric soul is a little more
上質な電気魂はもう少し
So would be able to make this
それでこれを作ることができるでしょう
good
良い
So
それで
This thing Tapioca also has toxins
このタピオカにも毒素がある
Also inside the rooting or quick-rooting bark
発根または早い根の樹皮の内側にも
glycoside
配糖体
Green acid is
青酸就是
when everyone wants to commit suicide
誰もが自殺したいとき
just eat this
これを食べるだけ
But I didn't finish half of what I just said.
しかし、私は今言ったことの半分も終えていません。
That is to say, this Tapioca is very important in Africa
つまり、このタピオカはアフリカではとても重要なのです
The main reason is that those places in Africa do not have enough water
主な理由は、アフリカのそれらの場所には十分な水がないことです
You can't grow sweet potatoes, but you can grow them
サツマイモは育てられないけど育てることはできる
but not too successful
しかしあまり成功していない
Then grow this Tapioca
それからこのタピオカを育ててください
The local people of the Tapioca people are very active
タピオカ族の地元の人たちはとても活発です
So it can't wait to dig out the root and eat it
根を掘り出して食べるのが待ちきれません
so the problem is big
だから問題は大きい
The problem is that it's not mature enough to take root
問題は根付くほど成熟していないことだ
It just doesn't grow roots
ただ根が生えてないだけ
It is the unripe root, the root block
それは未熟な根、根のブロックです
After eating it, it will produce green acid
食べると緑色の酸が出ます
Anyone who knows a little chemistry can see that
少し化学を知っている人なら誰でもそれがわかるでしょう
This is the source of cyanic acid
これがシアン酸の原料です
this is a big problem
これは大きな問題です
then we will soon
それではすぐに行きます
is there any time here
ここに時間はありますか
time comparison
時間比較
Tomato
トマト
Tomato is another Solannam
トマトもソランナムです
I bind the peril
私は危険を縛ります
Ligo is
リゴは
Long
長さ
Pericum is peach
ペリカムは桃です
Tao
人
This is from
これはからです
Mexico B. Lu Gaudi
メキシコ B. ル・ガウディ
This should read B
これは B と読みます。
this country
この国
before
以前也
Once became B Lu by himself
かつては一人でB Luになった
Not Peru
ペルーではありません
This is
これは
marjoram
マージョラム
go to the philippines
フィリピンに行く
Then what
じゃあ何
Just isolate
ただ隔離するだけ
spread very fast
非常に早く広がりました
imagine this now
今これを想像してください
to an italian restaurant
イタリアンレストランへ
no escape
逃げ場はありません
Before going to the museum
美術館に行く前に
not italian
イタリア人ではありません
often in usa
アメリカではよくある
work
仕事
The question is, is it a fruit or a vegetable?
問題は、それが果物なのか、それとも野菜なのかということです。
Both fruits and vegetables are good and nutritious
野菜も果物も美味しくて栄養価が高い
so what is
それで何ですか
So this is from Tomato
これはトマトからです
the origin of this phrase
この言葉の由来
Asthex is called Citomato
アステックスはシトマトと呼ばれます
What about the rest of Central America?
中米の残りの地域はどうですか？
Just get rid of this first Ciraba
この最初のシラバを取り除くだけです
Screaming Tomato
叫 Tomato
Then when you go to Australia or Italy?
では、オーストラリアやイタリアに行くときは？
don't use this
これは使わないでください
It's called Pomodoro
それをポモドーロといいます
Pomo means Apple
ポモとはアップルのことです
Doro is gold
ドロは金だ
golden apple
金のりんご
Then the discourse is called Pom de Moll
そしてその談話は「ポム・ド・モール」と呼ばれる
What about this? Actually, if you say
これはどうですか? 実は、こう言うと
If it is directly released, it is the apple of love
そのまま放てば愛の林檎
But it has nothing to do with love
でもそれは恋愛とは関係ない
you love
あなたは愛しています
Ask someone to eat this apple and it won't love you more
誰かにこのリンゴを食べてもらっても、あなたをこれ以上愛してはくれないでしょう
It is said that the document I read recently said this
最近読んだ文書にはこう書かれていたそうです
This one originally meant this Pom de Mour
これはもともとこのポム・ド・ムールを意味していました
It's the Mu'er people, the people in northern Africa.
それは北アフリカのムエル族です。
What about these people, just call this eggplant this
この人たちはどうですか、このナスをこれと呼んでください
France is anti-made this called Pom de Mour
フランスはポム・ド・ムールと呼ばれる反作です
So don't give your lover too much Tomato
だから恋人にトマトを与えすぎないでください
what about when i go somewhere else
他の場所に行くときはどうですか
only see this thing
これしか見えない
tomato on tree
木の上のトマト
Then Taiwan also has
それから台湾にもあります
not native is there
ネイティブではありません
yes yes
はいはい
So this thing is
それで、これは
Actually, it's the tomato tree
実はトマトの木なんです
I ate several of them and they were pretty good, just like the usual fairy tales
いくつか食べましたが、いつものおとぎ話のようにとても美味しかったです
Well, of course, the ingredients in the tomato are only quite good, that is, the soup is a little less
まあ、もちろん、トマトの具材はかなり良いだけです、つまり、スープは少し少ないです
The water side is also a little less, but the taste is quite high
水辺も少し少ないですが、味はかなり高いです
And this is the medium production of China, the United States, Turkey, India, etc.
そして、これは中国、米国、トルコ、インドなどの中規模の生産です。
In terms of crowds, these numbers are different
混雑に関しては、これらの数字は異なります
However, the most important source of use in tomatoes is a product, which is lycopene
しかし、トマトの最も重要な利用源は製品であり、それはリコピンです。
It is a major anti-oxygen antioxidant
それは主要な抗酸素抗酸化物質です
Then also the predecessor of this carotenoid
そして、このカロテノイドの前身でもあります
So, Tomato is a tomato that has quite a different value
つまり、トマトは全く異なる価値を持つトマトです
We don't need to talk about this anymore
これについてはもう話す必要はありません
What I want to tell you is
私があなたに伝えたいのは、
Holidays can leave the release of Tomato Flavor Elements
祝日はトマトフレーバーエレメントのリリースをお休みすることができます
Then look at the next one
それでは次を見てください
But this first
でもまずはこれ
one
一個
Interjection is to say that the United States is said
間投詞は、米国が言っていると言うことです
If your dog is sprayed by this shy boy
もしあなたの犬がこの内気な少年にスプレーされたら
it stinks very stinky
とても臭いです
Can't be washed off with flying photos
飛んできた写真は洗い流せない
so what to do
じゃあ何をすればいいの
They just say use this
彼らはこれを使用すると言っているだけです
tomato
Tomato來洗
Tomato Juice to wash
洗うトマトジュース
Because of the lake bottle thing
レイクボトルのせいで
is polyunsaturated
多価不飽和である
It's hard to live
生きるのは難しい
So the smelly thing it sprays out is called
それで、それが吹き出す臭いものは呼ばれます
Milk Captain
ミルクキャプテン
So it can be quickly absorbed by this hair
この髪にすぐに吸収されるので、
But let's be honest
でも正直に言いましょう
You don't have to commit a crime when you take your dog out in the wild
犬を野外に連れ出すのに犯罪を犯す必要はない
guilty and beside
有罪でありながらも
so to be honest
正直に言うと
So it's better to fight with small trees
だから、小さな木と戦う方が良いです
Add this peroxide core
この過酸化物コアを追加します
Then it will be fine after oxidation.
酸化後は大丈夫です。
good
良い
Well, half of what I just said
まあ、今言ったことの半分は
It is only when Lycopin is heated that it can be released
リコピンは加熱された場合にのみ放出されます
This is when there is no heat
この時は熱がないので
It becomes brighter after heating
加熱すると明るくなります
So after heating it releases
したがって、加熱後に放出されます
Then there is a simultaneous experiment
それでは同時実験です
Do Vitamin C Thoroughly
ビタミンCをしっかり摂る
Vitamin C is not as fragile as everyone thinks
ビタミンCはみんなが思っているほど壊れやすいわけではない
It goes through 80 degrees is 30 minutes at least -1
80度を通るのは最低30分 -1
20 percent only
20パーセントだけ
So it doesn't hurt too much
なのであまり痛くないですよ
However, during this period, the Lai Kepin has increased a lot
しかし、この間にライ・ケピンは大幅に増加しました。
The function of this Lai Kepin is quite good
このライ・ケピンの機能はかなり良いです
Mainly sunscreen
日焼け止め
And its active strength is 10 times stronger than Vitamin E
その活性力はビタミンEの10倍です。
Twice as much as Kyler's Note so pretty good
カイラーのメモの2倍なのでかなり良い
So love or not, you can eat more of this
好き嫌いに関わらず、これをもっと食べてもいいよ
ease
簡易
Well, maybe you think this
まあ、おそらくあなたはこう思うでしょう
Catchup is used
キャッチアップが使用されます
In kyogen, the word looks like this
狂言ではこんな言葉になります。
right
右
This is the catchup could be this
これがキャッチアップです
then come back
それから戻ってください
Peanuts
ピーナッツ
occur
起こる
I prefer to fall
私は落ちるほうが好きです
the intention to lose it when it happens
それが起こったときにそれを失うつもり
Ditto is ok
同様に大丈夫です
Longevity Fruit Too Severe and Deep Imperial Physician
厳しすぎる長寿の果実 帝国の医師
The imperial doctor's dirt bucket and wide bucket can do it
帝国医師の土バケツとワイドバケツならできる
In Japanese it is called Tang Ren Dou
日本語では唐仁堂といいます。
Nanjing bucket
南京バケツ
is to indicate its source
出典を示すことです
it is imported from china
中国から輸入されています
That's why it's called Tangrendou
だから唐蓮堂と呼ばれる
Nanjing bucket
南京バケツ
Then look at this seed
じゃあこの種を見てください
The production volume is still China's No. 1 in India, etc., etc.
生産量は今でも中国第1位、インド等でもある。
so
それで
In fact, Taiwanese pronunciation is quite natural.
実は台湾語の発音はとても自然なのです。
more vocal than other countries
他国に比べて声が大きい
i think so
そう思います
The spoken word is also
話し言葉も、
Spaniards are closer to earthfish
スペイン人は地球魚に近い
like chili
唐辛子のような
it's still called chili
それはまだチリと呼ばれています
Spain is called Wette
スペインはウェッテと呼ばれます
Germany is called Archnus
ドイツはArchnusと呼ばれています
bean of soil
土の豆です
Of course it doesn't make sense for me to mention this
もちろん私がこれについて言及しても意味はありません
with italian etc.
イタリア語などで
German and Dutch etc are two systems
ドイツ語とオランダ語などは 2 つのシステムです
whatever you call it
あなたがそれを何と呼んでも
vocalization is very
発声はとても
very high volume
非常に大音量
Where is the height?
高さはどこですか？
Because the heat is not too high
熱もそこまで高くないので
The heat of the fire rice comes from the main body and from the main yellow
火ご飯の熱は本体とメインの黄色から出ます
Soup is not high
スープは高くない
1,000 yuan for a pig is a bit higher
豚1​​000元はちょっと高い
then the protein is very high
それからタンパク質は非常に高いです
And this one has very, very high offshore acid
そして、これは非常に高いオフショア酸を持っています
So you eat corn best with
したがって、トウモロコシを食べるのに最も適しているのは、
peanuts to cultivate
栽培する落花生
So you can make up this offshore acid
それで、この沖合の酸を補うことができます
Then these various
それからこれらのさまざまな
it is enough
それは十分です
So let's talk about this
それでは、これについて話しましょう
Fanshiliu
番石流
guava
グアバ
what about this
これはどうですか
its origin is not clear
その起源は明らかではありません
Because very early on it was
非常に早い段階でそうであったため、
probably from
おそらくから
Into the Americas from southern Mexico
メキシコ南部からアメリカ大陸へ
Then what
じゃあ何
the entire interior of the Americas
アメリカ大陸の内陸全体
with the West Indies, etc.
西インド諸島などと。
islands are
島々は
Guo Lunbu hasn't entered yet
郭倫武はまだ入っていない
It has spread a little bit before reaching the U.S.
アメリカに伝わる前に少しずつ広まりました。
then of course
それならもちろん
maybe not later
たぶん後ではない
spread more widely
より広く普及する
So
それで
This is Spread Before Columbus
これはコロンブス以前に広まったものです
then this
それからこれ
this
これ
What about Leo's name?
レオの名前はどうですか？
Celium Guajaba
セリウム グアジャバ
Reflected in Spanish
スペイン語で反映
spanish french
スペイン語 フランス語
All use this Guajaba
みんなこのグアジャバを使ってます
GU A-Handle-Hanging Art
GU A-ハンドルハンギングアート
wait wait wait wait
待って待って待って
So why is Taiwan called Bala?
では、なぜ台湾はバラと呼ばれるのでしょうか？
I don't have this yet
これはまだ持っていません
full of explanations
説明がいっぱい
The advanced possibilities of everyone here
ここにいるみんなの高度な可能性
will teach me
私に教えてくれるでしょう
why this
なぜこれ
Bala in Taiwan
台湾のバラ
where did i come from
私はどこから来たのですか
So the world's
それで世界の
None of this
これはどれも
The difference is
違いは
Abbas of Guam
グアムのアッバス
it's quite different
それは全く違います
Nothing like this one in Bala
バラにはこれに似たものはありません
the noun
名詞
good
良い
Look at its nutritional value
その栄養価を見てみましょう
not too hot
暑すぎない
The wind is not too high
風もそれほど強くない
fiber is a lot
繊維が多い
But the microphone is also quite impressive
しかし、マイクも非常に印象的です
A wide variety of sanitation is good
色々衛生的で良いですね
But the best thing is
でも一番いいのは
Bitem is very high
バイトが非常に高い
So
それで
Plus things like Baili
さらに、百里のようなもの
It is said
と言われています
According to this document
この文書によると
is very functional
非常に機能的です
that's what they say
それが彼らが言うことです
common sense barra can lower
常識的なバーラは下げることができます
type 2 diabetes
2型糖尿病
So Taiwan has four seasons
台湾には四季があるのですね
All produce this Fanshiliu
すべてがこのFanshiliuを生み出します
output is large
出力が大きい
According to my guess, there are few in the whole country
推測ですが、全国的にも少ないと思います
so what
だから何
All Barra water is good
バラの水はどれもとても美味しいです
also have problems
問題もあります
But needless to say
しかし言うまでもなく
Well, I've probably already said this
まあ、これはもう言ったかもしれませんが、
One thing I also pointed out is that
私も指摘したことの一つは、
Way stream leaves are also very useful
ウェイストリームの葉も非常に便利です
It's probably not like before when we went to the country when we were kids
私たちが子供の頃に田舎に行ったときとはおそらく違うでしょう
He sees this way the leaves that flow into tea attack women
お茶に流れ込む葉が女性を襲う様子を彼は見ている
So this is a very generous kind of thing
これはとても寛大なことです
I probably don't have such a good thing now
たぶん今はそんな良いものはない
This can be seen look at this
これを見ればわかります
Bai Lamin is one person equal to three oranges
バイラミンはオレンジ 3 個に相当します
Sometimes three oranges are too much to eat
オレンジ3個では食べきれないこともある
Then just eat one and eat one spicy enough
それから、1つ食べて、1つだけ十分に辛いものを食べてください
Talk about this square sauce chili
この四角いソースチリについて話してください
Chili is also eaten quite early
唐辛子もかなり早くから食べられます
It turned out that the remixing started in Beijing
リミックスは北京で始まったことが判明
it was in the southwest
南西部にありました
It is said so
そう言われています
The ship also passes through the Philippines and India
船はフィリピンとインドも通過
Then in China, Indonesia, Korea, Japan
その後中国、インドネシア、韓国、日本でも
The engineering department also brought directly to Spain, Fortaur
エンジニアリング部門もスペインに直接導入したフォルタウル社
This pepper can be divided into three types
この唐辛子は3種類に分けられます
Green Peppers, Chili Peppers, Chili Peppers
グリーンペッパー、チリペッパー、チリペッパー
The reason for this spiciness is a substance called capsaicin
この辛さの原因はカプサイシンという物質です
capsaicin
カプサイシン
This is actually in medicine now
これは実際に今医学の中にあります
You can also use this
これも使えます
When doing this various medicine
これを行うときにさまざまな薬
There must be several doctors who can confirm this
これを確認できる医師は何人もいるはずです
have a good one
良いものを持っている
there are birds
鳥がいます
just lacking on this chili
この唐辛子が足りないだけ
But the birds are not spicy when they eat these things
でも鳥はこれらのものを食べても辛くない
Of course it doesn't matter
もちろん関係ありません
why i don't know
なぜ分からないのか
I don't know why there is any advantage
なんでメリットがあるのか​​わからない
Beef is not spicy
牛肉は辛くない
then the next thing is very interesting
それから次はとても興味深いです
And the story of its origin goes like this
そして、その起源の物語は次のようになります
Not a soil genus for a deficiency
欠乏のための土壌属ではない
then you can also see
それならあなたも見ることができます
It's not easy for mortals to fall in love
定命の者が恋に落ちるのは簡単ではない
But the princess fell in love with this handsome
でもお姫様はこのハンサムな男に恋をした
Of course the one who falls in love must be handsome
もちろん恋する人はイケメンに違いない
Probably not feed it Tomato
おそらくトマトを与えないでください
Then this pair of relatives escaped from their father's arrest
その後、この一組の親戚は父親の逮捕から逃れました
This is often a myth or an old story
これはたいてい神話や昔話です
This is very cruel
これはとても残酷です
they were arrested inside tropical sage
彼らはトロピカルセージの中で逮捕された
And be beheaded
そして斬首される
this is very cruel
これはとても残酷です
Then their seats stay on the ground
その後、彼らの座席は地面に残ります
become this thing
こうなる
This is Vanilla's story
これはバニラの物語です
This is where Vanilla comes from
バニラの由来はここから
There are of course stories like this everywhere.
もちろん、このような話はどこにでもあります。
This is a story of Vanilla
これはバニラの物語です
Vanilla's wind walk is also a bit weird
バニラの風の散歩もちょっと変
Because it's not China anymore
もう中国じゃないから
not america
アメリカではない
Vanilla is a country
バニラは国です
China also has it, but I have big ideas
中国にもありますが、私には大きなアイデアがあります
Mexico etc.
メキシコなど
Because what Vanilla found was a French doctor
バニラが見つけたのはフランス人の医師だったから
French doctors later transplanted him to
フランスの医師は後に彼を次の場所に移植しました。
an island in a certain french pavilion
とあるフランス館の島
later planted
後で植えた
The plant is growing
植物は成長しています
But it won't be able to receive
でも受信できなくなるよ
I said that Vanilla just talked about it
ヴァニラがそれについて話したばかりだと言いました
The things I saw just now can't grow
今見たものは成長できない
later they found out
後で彼らは知った
One of their efforts compared to a very smart effort
非常に賢明な取り組みと比較した彼らの取り組みの 1 つ
i think he found out
彼は気づいたと思う
because there is no
ないから
There is no certain wind to medium this hair powder
このヘアパウダーはミディアムに一定の風はありません
Later this clever effort
その後、この賢い取り組みが
invented this so-called artificial pollination method
このいわゆる人工授粉法を発明した
To be able to deliver this vanilla up
このバニラを届けられるように
able to be strong
強くなれる
So he won't be the one you normally see
だから彼はあなたがいつも見るような人ではないでしょう
Compared with the crispy corn, there are more residual crispy
クリスピーコーンに比べてクリスピーの残りが多い
then this i like very much
それからこれはとても気に入っています
I ask the source of this corn
このトウモロコシの出所を尋ねます
What about the term Vanilla?
バニラという言葉はどうでしょうか？
It was only in 1989 that there was this Barneyland
このバーニーランドが存在したのは 1989 年のことです。
This is from Barneyland
バーニーランドからです
Baccarat
バカラ
latin is parnylan
ラテン語はパルニランです
It's Xiaolizi
小莉子です
One very important thing is
非常に重要なことが 1 つあります
Flavor after fermentation
発酵後の風味
there is no way you put it there
そこに置く方法はありません
It must be treated in some way to have a scent
香りを付けるためには何らかの処理が必要です
what's inside benylon
ベニロンの中には何が入っているのか
There is a direction, this join has fermentation technology
方向性がある、この接合には発酵技術がある
can see this
これを見ることができます
Pippi and Marilyn
ピッピとマリリン
Marilyn sometimes this is called a candy
マリリンは時々これをキャンディーと呼びます
so what
だから何
These two are the most important direction components
これら 2 つは最も重要な方向コンポーネントです
So
それで
So now about this chocolate
さて、今回はこのチョコレートについて
chocolate
チョコレート
chocolate this
チョコレートこれ
This number is called
この番号はと呼ばれます
Til Brown Mocha High
ティル ブラウン モカ ハイ
Thiel is a god
ティールは神だ
Bronmore is food
ブロンモアは食べ物です
water of god
神の水
In fact, they often eat this chocolate in the king of aspen juice, for example.
実際、彼らはこのチョコレートをよく食べます。たとえば、アスペンジュースの王様
he doesn't eat this chocolate
彼はこのチョコレートを食べません
They eat the thick jelly of this tissue
彼らはこの組織の濃厚なゼリーを食べます
This is about 1100
これは1100くらいです
Said relatively new discovery
比較的新しい発見と言われました
It was produced by China and the United States
生産したのは中国とアメリカ
here are black and white chocolate
こちらは黒と白のチョコレートです
White chocolate is not real chocolate
ホワイトチョコレートは本物のチョコレートではありません
why
なぜ
because it is not without this chocolate
このチョコレートなしではいられないから
what i told you just now
今私が言ったこと
so chocolate has several things
チョコレートにはいくつかの特徴があります
so very important
とても重要です
this is the most important
これが最も重要です
Fanel et alamin
フェニルETアミン
Fanis
Fanis安
This thing is a neural address
これはニューラルアドレスです
This means you feel good and comfortable after eating it
つまり、食べた後は気分が良くて快適になります
so you don't have to send this tomato
だからこのトマトを送る必要はないよ
send some chocolate
チョコレートをください
There is also this Theodore Bramins
こんなセオドア・ブラミンズもいる
This is very similar to caffeine
これはカフェインによく似ています
The difference is this place
違うのはこんなところ
There is this clip machine in the coffee
コーヒーの中にこのクリップマシンがあります
not here
ここにはいない
It's not important that its function is almost the same
機能がほぼ同じであることは重要ではありません
So white chocolate doesn't have those things
ホワイトチョコレートにはそんなものはありません
So your white chocolate is free
だからあなたのホワイトチョコレートは無料です
Not only free gift but also harm
無償の贈り物だけでなく損害も発生する
why do harm
なぜ害を及ぼすのか
Because it contains Coconut Butter
ココナッツバターが入っているので
cheese
チーズ
Fukalabada is all about saturated food
フカルバダは飽和食がすべてです
too many nights
夜が多すぎる
so you send white chocolate
ホワイトチョコレートを送ります
just want your lover to be early
ただ恋人に早く来てほしいだけ
having a heart attack etc.
心臓発作などを起こしている。
So give me a dark chocolate set
だからダークチョコレートセットをください
Let's talk about beans
豆について話しましょう
Beans Actually Every Week in New World Beans
新世界では実際に毎週ビーンズが登場します ビーンズ
are more expensive than the rule of law in Russia
ロシアの法の支配よりも費用がかかる
lots and lots of beans
たくさんの豆
Among them, there are many kinds of Taiwan
その中でも台湾の種類はたくさんあります
For example, the rule of law Russia we call Kidney Bean
たとえば、ロシアの法の支配をインドニービーンと呼んでいます。
Yellow Ground Bean Lemabini
黄地豆レマビニ
Lema is actually a
レマは実際には
In picture one is about the emperor
写真の 1 つは天皇についてのものです
Inge also means emperor
インゲは皇帝という意味もあります
So this is what Emperor Bean means
これがエンペラービーンの意味です
It's all against
全部反対だよ
So this is a lot of land
それで、ここは広い土地です
Many other beans are freshly poured in
他にも淹れたての豆がたくさんあります。
so i just said
だから私はちょうど言った
If you eat corn, you must supplement it with beans.
トウモロコシを食べる場合は、豆で補う必要があります。
In other words, you only need ten items on nutrition.
つまり、必要な栄養は10項目だけ。
Finally I talk about these plants
最後にこれらの植物について話します
I'll start by telling you about the Fromosa Plants
まずはフロモサ植物についてご紹介します
It was written by the priest Mr. Pan Fujun
僧侶の潘富君氏が書いたものです。
This sign is inserted from his book
この看板は彼の著書から挿入されたものです
Well, what happened to the corn turned the book, actually I already talked about it
さて、本をひっくり返したトウモロコシに何が起こったのか、実はそれについてはすでに話しました
sleep
寝る
Probably none of you didn't expect that you brought it to America with your own hands.
おそらく皆さんの中には、自分の手でそれをアメリカに持ち込んだとは誰も予想していなかったでしょう。
papaya is also pineapple
パパイヤもパイナップルです
I thought the pineapple was from Taiwan but it wasn't
パイナップルは台湾産かと思ってましたが違いました
Pumpkin is not Freddie and certainly not cassava and neither
カボチャはフレディではありませんし、もちろんキャッサバでもありません
Passion fruit is not strawberry nor is it
パッションフルーツはイチゴでもイチゴでもありません
look at its orchid garden
蘭園を見てください
In the early days, most of them passed through the Philippines
初期の頃は、そのほとんどがフィリピンを経由していました。
Of course it's not that simple
もちろんそれほど単純ではありません
But whenever we see, for example,
しかし、たとえば、私たちが見るたびに、
also through the Philippines
フィリピン経由でも
It may also come via the mainland
大陸経由で来ることもある
Everything that comes from sleep is pretended
眠りから生まれるすべてはふりだ
Then papaya and so on are all troubles
それからパパイヤとかも全部大変だよ
Closer means
近いという意味
The genus is from Brazil through the South Island of Southeast Asia
この属はブラジルから東南アジアの南島が原産です。
Baixiang fruit is brought by the Japanese
白香の果実は日本人がもたらしたもの
Strawberries are also brought by the Japanese
イチゴも日本人が持ち込んだもの
But of course it's originally from the New World.
しかし、それはもちろん新世界から来たものです。
so far we have only talked about plants
これまでは植物についてのみ話してきました
We are not partial to plants
私たちは植物にこだわらない
But because most of the things from the New World
しかし、ほとんどのものは新世界から来たものなので、
more plants
もっと植物を
Then you think about what kind of New World
それからあなたはどんな新世界かを考えます
This animal can attack the Old World
この動物は旧世界を攻撃することができます
including Taiwan
台湾も含めて
can you name a few
いくつか挙げていただけますか
but food
でも食べ物
So animals don't move much food over there
だから動物たちはそこに食べ物をあまり移動させない
this
これ
This is also quite
これもなかなか
This is Shenzhen, a native of the United States
こちらはアメリカ出身の深センです
Now there's this wildfire machine
今、この山火事マシンがあります
Of course, now is the time for the so-called temperature-sensitive world
もちろん、今はいわゆる温度に敏感な世界の時代です。
is a lot
たくさんあります
then this
それからこれ
how come
どうして
The other is overturning
もう一つはひっくり返る
This is me a few months ago half a year ago
これは数ヶ月前の半年前の私です
Overturned photos taken outside Ulu
ウルの外で撮影されたひっくり返った写真
They still have pressure
彼らにはまだプレッシャーがある
I don't quite understand that winter progresses
冬が進むのがよくわからない
I can't think of anything to do with this
これと何の関係も思いつきません
It's weird to appear on the stage
ステージに立つのは変だ
why i don't know
なぜ分からないのか
Then only in this
じゃあこれだけで
I experienced it myself
私自身も経験しました
Sauce duck, honey duck, etc.
ソース鴨、ハニー鴨など。
So these two birds
それでこの二羽の鳥は
just compare
ただ比較してください
animal that produces more food
より多くの食物を生産する動物
per continent per continent
大陸ごと 大陸ごと
never looked like a cow
決して牛に見えなかった
Or animals like pigs don't have
あるいは豚のような動物にはありません
this is for many reasons
これには多くの理由があります
I don't have time to talk about that now
今はそれについて話す時間がありません
some are some
いくつかはいくつか
then this is not food
それならこれは食べ物ではない
But there is a very influential thing is tobacco
しかし、非常に影響力のあるものはタバコです
I'll talk about this before I talk about tobacco
タバコの話をする前にこのことについて話します
Solanan
ソラナン
A lot of this pig in this family is food
この家族の豚の多くは食料です
So is Gou Ji
ゴジもそうだよ
Tobacco Of course many of these things belong to Solanan
タバコ もちろんこれらの多くはソラナンのものです
Tobacco belongs to this too
タバコもこれに属します
Then everyone knows Nicotin
そうすれば誰もがニコチンを知っています
The impact of this tobacco is not only on Taiwan
このタバコの影響は台湾だけではない
Great influence all over the world
全世界都非常大的影響
not food
食べ物ではありません
But the biggest impact
でも最大のインパクトは
then when we were kids
それから私たちが子供の頃
We went to learn that the digital product of Taiwan's main business is ABCSR
台湾の主力事業のデジタル製品がABCSRであることを知りに行ってきました
very different now
今は全然違う
A is for anana
A是anana
This is Pineapple
これはパイナップルです
dividend
配当
B is of course banana
Bはもちろんバナナです
C is for elder
Cは年長者
Campfer
カンプファー
S is of course sugar
Sはもちろん砂糖です
R is for rice
Rはお米です
T
T
different now
今は違う
C may be computer
Cはコンピュータかもしれない
Everyone didn't know for a while
しばらくみんな知らなかった
Anyway, this is very different from now
とにかく今とは大きく違います
So
それで
girls dating
デート中の女の子
We Colombus
私たちコロンバス
provide us with many things
私たちに多くのものを与えてくれる
So what's coming back in Asia
アジアでは何が戻ってくるのか
First
初め
The big thing is soybeans
大事なのは大豆です
Soybeans are very very very high impact
大豆は非常に非常に大きな影響を与えます
The other one is the duck
もう一人はアヒルです
Then I won't talk about the other one now
じゃあもう一つについては今は話さないよ
I'll talk about it later
それについては後で話します
So let's talk about soybeans first
それではまず大豆について話しましょう
soybeans sleeping in england
イギリスに眠っている大豆
Suo Yabing
スオ・ヤビン
then in
それから
America is Suo Yibing
アメリカはスオ・イービンだ
soya ice
大豆氷
in japanese
日本語で
soy sauce is called soy sauce
醤油は醤油といいます
so what about this
それで、これはどうですか
from
から
Soya ice comes from soy sauce
しょうゆ氷は醤油から生まれる
then the United States
それから米国
The United States likes to put some things
米国は何かを置くのが好きだ
shorten
短くする
simplify
簡略化する
Suo Yibing
ソ・イービン
what about soybeans
大豆はどうですか
Of course you can make tofu
もちろん豆腐も作れます
Soy sauce is also doing very well in the United States now
醤油も現在アメリカで非常に好調です
Soybean oil
大豆油
Natto
納豆
No
いいえ
Natto everyone is also very popular in Taiwan
みなさん納豆は台湾でも大人気
often do things
よく物事をする
then there is soy sauce
それから醤油があります
So very popular in America
まあ、アメリカでは大人気なんですが、
Elamame means
エラマメとは
that is
あれは
It's written in Japanese
日本語で書かれています
soy beans
大豆
So
それで
hygienic soup
衛生的なスープ
Sanitary soup this time
今回は衛生スープ
then this is
それならこれは
China passes through the UK
中国が英国を通過
to the United States
アメリカへ
Then soybean production
それから大豆の生産
America is thirty-five percent
アメリカは35パーセント
brazil is twenty seven
ブラジルは27歳
argentina is nineteen
アルゼンチンは19歳です
China is less
中国は少ないよ
so what
だから何
this is an asian
これはアジア人です
non into columbus one
コロンバスワンには乗らない
elephant
象
So
それで
Of course this
もちろんこれ
Then tell another
それから別の人に言ってください
that is
あれは
peking duck
北京ダック
in the US is called
アメリカではそう呼ばれています
Nagashima duck
長島鴨
in America
アメリカでは
duck just compare
アヒルただ比較してください
the small one
小さいもの
salary increase industry
給与業界
but
しかし
Every year there are so many
毎年たくさんあります
of
の
chicken and turkey
チキンとターキー
Well, there are fewer ducks
まあ、アヒルは少ないです
but
しかし
The main thing is more than 90 percent
肝心なのは90パーセント以上
it's long island duck
ロングアイランドダックです
Long Island is Long Island
ロングアイランドはロングアイランドだよ
New York
ニューヨーク
like nearby
近くのような
looks like this
このように見えます
It's exactly the same in Beijing
北京でも全く同じです
So in fact someone said yes
それで実際に誰かが「はい」と言いました
The Tang Island tooth in the United States is better than that in Beijing, China
米国の唐島の歯は中国の北京のものよりも優れています
possible
可能
So this is about this tooth seed again
それで、これは再びこの歯の種についてです
Yazi Beijing Ya is not actually Beijing
ヤジ北京ヤは実際には北京ではありません
Check it out
見てみな
it is nanjing tooth
南京歯です
So there is a story
そこで話があります
Anyway, Beijing Dental
とにかく、北京歯科
After Nanjing Teeth became Beijing Teeth
南京歯が北京歯になった後
It was only in the hands of the Americans in the 1973 era
それは1973年の時代にのみアメリカ人の手に渡った
Seven Beijing teeth go to the United States
北京の歯7本が米国へ
In the future, it will become a lot of output
将来的には大量生産になります
A chicken with more teeth than a turkey
七面鳥より歯が多い鶏
However, there are quite a lot of Beijing dental
しかし、北京の歯科はかなりたくさんあります
So
それで
Peking duck was originally Nanjing duck
北京ダックはもともと南京ダックでした
Later, when the five generations of fruit were opened
その後、五代の実が開いたとき
There is this river between Beijing and Nanjing
北京と南京の間にこの川があります
often up and down
頻繁に上がったり下がったり
At that time, Nanjing Duck gradually became Peking Duck
その頃、南京ダックは徐々に北京ダックになっていきました。
then look again
それからもう一度見てください
What about the cross mark cross mark cross mark I just mentioned?
さっき言ったバツ印バツ印はどうですか？
is this majestic
これは雄大ですか
Don is the tobacco we can say is given to us every week
ドンは私たちに毎週与えられると言えるタバコです
asian give them hall
アジア人は彼らにホールを与えます
It feels like this hall
こんな感じのホールです
The language of this church is English and it is called Sugar
この教会の言語は英語で、「Sugar」と呼ばれています
Sugar
砂糖
Arabia is that this is Sugar from Arabia
アラビアとは、これはアラビアの砂糖です
This is Boss Sugar
ボスシュガーです
Sugar from Indo to Sanskritito
インドからサンスクリット語までの砂糖
So now it's Sugar
さて、今度はシュガーです
Italy in Sugar
砂糖のイタリア
Budayain
ブダヤン
In ancient times
古代では
Ancient West
古代西
The other one is also Saccharis
もう一つもサッカリスです
So mostly through this kind of words
だから主にこの種の言葉を通して
In this Tang character, it is said that the rice character adds soup
この唐の文字では、米の文字がスープを加えると言われています
is a fresh word
新鮮な言葉です
what about this
これはどうですか
In fact, Tang has a long history
実は唐には長い歴史があります。
Indian record
インディアンの記録
it is south of india with this pole
このポールがあるのはインドの南です
then as far back as 8 centuries before the park
そして公園が誕生する8世紀前まで遡ります
Well, there are also records in China
まあ、中国にも記録はある
Just said it was from India
インドから来たって言ってた
so don't get close
だから近づかないでください
was found before the Gupda dynasty
グプダ王朝以前に発見された
It was the park 50 years ago
50年前はそこが公園だった
Don's proximity is very important
ドンの近さは非常に重要です
Before World War II After World War II
第二次世界大戦前 第二次世界大戦後
Taiwan's so-called governance of the Tang Dynasty
台湾のいわゆる唐の統治
nearly destroyed
ほぼ破壊された
then reply
それから返信する
The biggest difficulty is getting this sugar in and out
最大の困難はこの砂糖の出し入れです
If the sugar does not come in and out
糖が出たり入ったりしない場合
Zhichang is very, very difficult
志昌はとてもとても難しいです
just can't count
ただ数えられない
So whoever can access the sugar person's company first wins
つまり、砂糖担当者の会社に最初にアクセスできた人が勝ちです
So there are many economic
だから経済的なものもたくさんあるし、
This is not the original
これはオリジナルではありません
Okay so now when it comes to this
さて、これに関してはもう
During the Halsian Empire of North India
北インドのハルス帝国時代
there used to be this pie
昔このパイがありました
It's time to receive Changchao
チャンチャオを受け取る時間です
can learn this simple method
この簡単な方法を学ぶことができます
i also see
私も見ています
a certain minister of a certain dynasty
某王朝の某大臣
to murder the emperor
皇帝を殺害する
He gave him this candy every day
彼は毎日彼にこのキャンディーを与えました
He will probably eat later
彼はおそらく後で食べるでしょう
Of course it will become
当然そうなりますよ
Is this minister small?
この大臣は小さいですか？
What I read about diabetes
糖尿病について読んだこと
Or just stumbled across this thing I don't know
あるいは、私が知らないことに偶然出会っただけです
Anyway, there have been people who used sugar for reading a long time ago.
それにしても、昔から砂糖を使って読書をしていた人がいました。
So
それで
Bactonia, this is the so-called Great Alexander
バクトニア、これはいわゆるグレートアレクサンダーです
When the third land once made an expedition to India
かつて第三の地がインドへ遠征に行ったときのこと。
Just take these and this file is called Honey bearing weas
これらを取得すると、このファイルは Honey bearing weas と呼ばれます
It's not this file, it's sugar cane to bring back
このファイルではなく、持ち帰るのはサトウキビです
Breed in Mattonia
マトニアの品種
Well Columbus is from Kennedy Island
コロンブスはケネディ島出身です
Got sugarcane weave not brought into the US
米国に持ち込まれていないサトウキビ織りを入手
It sounds like Columbus is here
コロンブスが来たみたいですね
something to do with the queen here
ここの女王と何か関係があるのか
this relationship
この関係
I won't talk much
あまり話さないよ
so it goes through here to get dry
ここを通って乾燥します
In order to be able to grow dry in the United States
アメリカで乾燥しても栽培できるようにするために
so we'll get to this
それではこれに行きます
FDN in the United States recommends daily
米国のFDNは毎日推奨しています
Get out this 2000 to 2500 calories
この2000〜2500カロリーを排出してください
in the United States actually
実際にアメリカでは
calories out per day
1日あたりの消費カロリー
much more than this
これよりもはるかに多くの
For example, Cinnabon
たとえば、シナボン
Everyone's little Cinabon in the lot
みんなたくさんの小さなシナボン
American airports sell this
アメリカの空港ではこれが売られています
As soon as a Cinabon comes out, this is equal to
シナボンが出るとすぐにこれに等しい
123% of this stuff
この内容の 123%
a big bottle of cola
コーラの大きなボトル
it's about the same
それはほぼ同じです
Then there are so many Sherups in Pancake
それからパンケーキにはたくさんのコザクラインコがいます
ice cream 1 coffee has so much
アイスクリーム 1 コーヒーにはたくさんあります
so what
だから何
These things are very, very common to Americans
これらはアメリカ人にとって非常に一般的なものです
So FDS is now recommended
したがって、FDS が推奨されるようになりました
can only eat so much
たくさんしか食べられない
So the sugar community is too big
つまりシュガーコミュニティは大きすぎる
Everyone Knows To Be Fat
誰もが太っていることを知っています
diabetes patient
糖尿病患者
Also cures cancer, stops teeth and hurts liver
ガンを治し、歯を止め、肝臓を傷つける
These are all very serious consequences
これらはすべて非常に深刻な結果です
Recently, Americans have become more self-conscious
最近アメリカ人は自意識が強くなってきた
There was a doctor called Rovartalustic
ロヴァルタラスティックという医師がいました
It is the authority of the neurology of internal administration in the United States
米国内科学の神経内科の権威です
he once published a
彼はかつて出版した
Sugar The Beta Truth
シュガー・ザ・ベータ・トゥルース
Very Familiar Facts About Sugar
砂糖に関するよく知られた事実
That's what he said
それが彼が言ったことです
sugar is toxin
砂糖は毒素です
really makes sense
本当に意味がある
So you see now America
それで今のアメリカがわかります
Every time I come back to the U.S. from a foreign country
外国からアメリカに戻るたびに
The first thing I can see is the return of the Americans
最初に見えるのはアメリカ人の帰還だ
it's very scary
とても怖いです
So it makes sense for him, the doctor, to say that Down's family read books.
ですから、医師である彼が、ダウン君の家族は本を読んでいると言ったのは理にかなっていました。
So try your best to use this as your goal
だからこれを目標にして頑張ってください
This is actually a difference between men and women
実はこれが男性と女性の違いなのです
But anyway this
でもとにかくこれ
If you think about it, one Monday exceeds the calories of the whole day
考えてみれば月曜日が一日のカロリーを超えてしまう
so very very powerful
とてもとてもとても強力です
So look back at the short history
そこで短い歴史を振り返ってみましょう
Then it is the same as below
それでは以下と同じです
It is said that Zhenghe has also been to America, probably not
鄭和もアメリカに行ったことがあると言われていますが、おそらくそうではありません。
But if he comes
でももし彼が来たら
However, in America, Columbus was not so glorious
しかし、アメリカではコロンブスはそれほど栄光ではありませんでした
However, Columbus came to the United States on the 41st, 4th, 9th, 2nd
しかし、コロンブスは41日、4日、9日、2日にアメリカに来ました。
Finally, one or two years
結局1年か2年か
Exactly, I came to Taiwan a little later
そうです、私は少し遅れて台湾に来ました
Japan came to Taiwan later
日本はその後台湾にやって来ました
Therefore, after the actual arrival in the United States,
そのため、実際にアメリカに到着してからは、
The so-called topic I'm going to talk about today will be quite different.
今日私が話すいわゆるトピックは全く異なります
then, at the end
それから最後に
That's about the end of what I'm talking about
私が話していることはこれで終わりです
However, in the end, I would like to thank you all
でも、最後に皆さんに感謝したいと思います
There are a few people who can help
助けてくれる人が何人かいる
some people are here
何人かの人がここにいます
So, what about reference hazards
では、参照ハザードについてはどうでしょうか
in english, yes
英語で、はい
why we eat why we eat
なぜ食べるのか なぜ食べるのか
starter chocolate
スターターチョコレート
food america to the world
フードアメリカを世界へ
Also food in history
歴史上の食べ物も
This is Lie Yi Tae Xia
リー・イー・テシアです
It can be said that Qiao Wen has the most Qiao Wen's book is this
チャオ・ウェンの本が最も多いと言えるのはこれです
Written by Zugman
ザグマン著
This 1998 is the time when it was published
この本が出版されたのは1998年です
the original was earlier
オリジナルはもっと前だった
Potato
じゃがいも
How the humble spot
なんと地味なスポット
spot is the thing that goes fast
スポットは速く進むものです
Rescue the western world
西側世界を救おう
relatively new is
比較的新しいのは
Andrew Smith's Potato a global history
アンドリュー・スミスのポテトの世界史
I read all these books
私はこれらの本をすべて読みました
see all
すべてを見る
Then I just talked about this
それから私はちょうどこのことについて話しました
Written by Mr. Pan Fujun
潘富潤氏著
Smokey 朱继
スモーキー朱继
This Taiwanese food culture system
この台湾の食文化体系
These two wrote
この二人が書いたのは
Yaolan, a Taiwanese farmhouse, also has
台湾の農家ヤオランもあります
There are two very impressive books in Japanese
日本語で書かれた非常に印象的な本が2冊あります
This is written by Ben Jingjian
これはベン・ジンジャンが書いたものです
Satsuma billion horse is
サツマ億馬は
Another layer of the world of "Jackie Mo" written in Zhang characters
張文字で書かれた「ジャッキー・モー」の世界のもう一つの層
It is the world of Potato
それはポテトの世界です
Both sides are wonderfully written and very evil
どちらの面も素晴らしく書かれていますが、非常に邪悪です
Especially about the history of the development of feudal arts and foreign languages ​​in Japan
特に日本における封建芸術と外国語の発展の歴史について
is very very clear
とてもとても明確です
Finally thank you all
最後に皆さんに感謝します
Thank you Li Yuan Restaurant is a wonderful staff
Li Yuan Restaurantは素晴らしいスタッフです、ありがとうございます
I don't know if there is any problem doing it now
今やっても問題あるかどうかは分からない
please
お願いします
borrow a microphone
マイクを借ります
My question is to say
私の質問はこう言うことです
Basically I'm thinking of a question which is to say
基本的に私は次のような質問を考えています
Spaniards once came to Taiwan
かつてスペイン人が台湾にやって来た
Spaniards dated around 1626
1626年頃のスペイン人
Then the Dutch also came to Taiwan
その後、オランダ人も台湾にやって来ました
Then I was thinking that the Dutch came around this time in 1624
それから私はオランダ人が 1624 年のこの時期に来たのではないかと考えていました。
In other words, the migration of animals and plants in Taiwan came from these two lines
つまり、台湾における動植物の移動はこの2つの系統から来たということになる。
Because they went to the Philippines and Manila
フィリピンとマニラに行ったから
So it is said that the New World was brought from there.
新世界はそこからもたらされたと言われています。
It is possible that from the perspective of so we see a lot of conversations
という観点からすると、多くの会話が見られる可能性があります
There are many more like this, this, Batavia or Holland
これ、これ、バタビア、オランダなど、他にもたくさんあります
Or India then one of the things I want to ask I want to understand is say in New Zealand
インドか、それから私が聞きたいこと、理解したいことの一つは、ニュージーランドだと言うこと
This place in New Zealand is now Sri Lanka
ニュージーランドのこの場所は現在スリランカです
It was also occupied by the Netherlands in about 1652.
1652 年頃にはオランダにも占領されました。
They did a research on Potenacr one by one
彼らはポテナクルについて一つ一つ研究しました
They found out that the Dutch
彼らはオランダ人が
Because Zealand has a history of being occupied by the Netherlands and grapes
ジーランドはオランダとブドウに占領された歴史があるので
they found out
彼らは知った
after the dutch left
オランダ人が去った後
They did a species survey
彼らは種の調査をしました
It turned out that fifty percent
その50パーセントであることが判明した
It's exotic
エキゾチックです
In other words plants have an invisible velocity
言い換えれば、植物には目に見えない速度があるということです
invade zealand
ジーランドを侵略する
So my question is that
それで私の質問はそれです
If Taiwan is counted from the year 1624
台湾を1624年から数えると
The Dutch The Dutch have been in Taiwan for 42 years
オランダ人 オランダ人は台湾に住んで42年になります
After leaving, there must be an invisible speed
去ってからは目に見えないスピードがあるはず
bring all his stuff in
彼のものをすべて持ち込む
what about that thing
それはどうですか
That is, the academician may have talked about a lot
つまり、学者はたくさんのことを話したかもしれない
In terms of flipping or paste that thing
それを反転またはペーストするという点では
then just ask
それなら聞いてください
then Taiwan
それから台湾
Now building has a problem saying
今、建物には次のような問題があります
That is to say Taiwan
つまり台湾
Crash everywhere
どこでもクラッシュ
something is eating
何かが食べています
when talking so much
たくさん話しているとき
what is there in taiwan
台湾には何がありますか
this is my first question
これが私の最初の質問です
The second question is to say
2番目の質問はこう言うことです
The academician just said that there is a kind of vanilla
学者はバニラがあると言いました
Valina actually it's a Dutch
ヴァリナ、実はオランダ人なんです
Vanilla its flavor it is an orchid called Vanilla Orchid
バニラその風味はバニラオーキッドと呼ばれる蘭です
Vanilla's Lan OK
Vanilla的蘭 OK
Extract its flavor from that orchid
その蘭から香りを抽出
That is the fruit of a bean in the orchid
それは蘭の中の豆の実です
But what you just drew is a disease of a Vanilla
でも君が今描いたのはバニラの病気だ
this bean
この豆
But the problem is that orchids will not cure such a serious disease
しかし問題は、蘭ではそのような深刻な病気は治らないということです
So I'm thinking that this disease is related to the small seeds in the orchid's fruit
したがって、この病気は蘭の果実の中の小さな種子に関係しているのではないかと考えています。
So I'm thinking about this Vanilla disease
それで私はこのバニラ病について考えています
What is the difference between the so-called vanilla and the thing in the orchid? Two questions
いわゆるバニラと蘭のものの違いは何ですか? 2 つの質問
Thank you everyone
感謝大家
I hope you're not a pig
あなたが豚じゃないことを祈ります
Vanilla is indeed a orchid pig
バニラはまさに蘭の豚だ
But I just showed you that this tomato also has vines and trees.
しかし、このトマトには蔓や木も生えていることを先ほど紹介しました。
so it doesn't have to be your orchid pig just watch this
だから、あなたのランコの豚である必要はない、これを見てください
Usually used for home decoration
通常は家の装飾に使用されます
So Manila is really blue, tree art blue
マニラは本当に青、ツリーアートは青
And it has to change to be able to
そしてそれができるようになるためには変わらなければなりません
Only when Manila changes can there be things
マニラが変わるときだけ何かが起こる
So what I just said
それで、私が今言ったこと
Human beings must be burnt to be able to achieve transformation from birth to death
人間は誕生から死に至るまでの変容を達成するためには焼かれなければなりません
what about me
私はどうなの
Until now, only when you go to land can you eat in Manila
今までマニラでは陸に上がった時にしか食べられませんでした
About Not Just Plants
植物だけではないことについて
all other disseminated
他のすべての配布物
It doesn't have to be a simple path
単純な道である必要はない
so there are many paths to take
だから取るべき道はたくさんある
what about this
これはどうですか
Wisme Qing'an
ウィスム清安
We are not so simple
私たちはそれほど単純ではありません
It's not that you eat a macroclump
巨大塊を食べるわけではない
or what bacteria
または何の細菌ですか
will drop immediately
すぐに落ちます
This very depends on the period of your contact
これは連絡の期間によって大きく異なります
The purpose of contacting this party
この当事者への連絡の目的
For example, the Dutch came to Taiwan
たとえば、オランダ人が台湾に来ました。
Not very generous with the food they brought to Taiwan
台湾に持ち込んだ食べ物はあまり寛大ではない
Taiwanese people go to steal his to get Dutch beans
台湾人がオランダ豆を手に入れるために彼のものを盗みに行く
Dutch beans are not a free supply brought to Taiwan by the Dutch
オランダ豆はオランダ人によって台湾に無償で持ち込まれたものではありません
but stolen
しかし盗まれた
So this is not a line
だからこれは線ではない
So there may be many ways to talk about the sweet potato
サツマイモについてはいろいろな言い方があるかもしれません
so can't say
だから言えない
I think Wang Fufu is probably smarter than me
王福福はおそらく私より賢いと思います
history does not appear
履歴が表示されない
I don't know if I answered your question or not
あなたの質問に答えたかどうかわかりません
I want to share something and raise a question
何かを共有したい、質問したい
That Gava 516, I once heard the director of the Mandarin Association talk about it
あのガバ516、マンダリン協会の会長が話していたのを聞いたことがある
Nabala is the language of their Paiwan people
ナバラ語はパイワン族の言語です
Paiwan language is called Nabbat, it is N-A, then a V-A-T
パイワン語はナバットと呼ばれ、N-A、次に V-A-T になります。
It seems that the Paiwan language is developed independently, and there are also such sayings
パイワン語は独自に発達した言語だそうで、こんな言い伝えもあります
Nabbat is used in the south, and Nabbat has many sounds
ナバットは南部で使用されており、ナバットには多くの音があります
I once went to Yunnan, China to see a kind of Nabbat
私はある種のナバットを見に中国の雲南省に行ったことがある
Our general Balat size is probably like this or like this, right?
私たちの一般的なバラットのサイズはおそらくこんな感じかこんな感じですよね？
It used to be like this, but after improvement, it will look like this
以前はこうでしたが、改良後はこんな感じになります
The kid I saw in Yunnan had such a big head
雲南で見た子供はとても頭が大きかった
big
大
right
右
that tree too
あの木も
also that
それも
rice water stove tree
米水ストーブの木
same tree same leaves
同じ木同じ葉
I myself am
私自身も
also learn this
これも学びましょう
so i think
だから私は思う
strangeness
奇妙さ
why so big
なぜそんなに大きいのか
should be delicious
おいしいはずです
It turned out to be nasty
それは厄介なものであることが判明した
then i go
では行きます
go with him
彼と一緒に行きます
sometimes you that
時々あなたはそれを
Why is this white spicy food so unpalatable?
この白いスパイシーな食べ物はなぜこんなに不味いのでしょうか？
He said
彼は言った
what white spicy
なんて白いスパイシーさ
I said that not only what is this called
私は、これを何と呼ぶだけではないと言いました
Xiangyu
項羽
nice name
素敵な名前
elephant area
象域
I just thought about it
ちょっと考えてみたんですが
domain domain dead domain
ドメイン ドメイン デッドドメイン
Then I said how to eat this
それから私はこれをどうやって食べるか言いました
He said
彼は言った
eat with honey
蜂蜜と一緒に食べる
how to eat
食べ方
oh
おお
that's all
それで全部です
but i think
しかし、私は思います
if say
言うなら
in the country of origin
原産国で
If say in South America
南米で言えば
Origin unknown
起源不明
because
なぜなら
His little boy has such a big head
彼の小さな男の子はとても頭が大きい
It's delicious. It's really big.
美味しいですね、本当に大きいですね。
I bought two and both were terrible
2つ買ったけどどっちもひどかった
then i don't know what to say
それなら何を言えばいいのか分からない
is it from there
そこからですか
to Yunnan
雲南行き
the one in the mountains
山の中にあるもの
To be at the place where Teng Zichong
滕子充の場所に行くこと
right
右
but so big
でもとても大きい
I doubt it
疑わしい
strange that
奇妙なこと
he can't possibly go there
彼はそこには行けそうにない
As a result, he didn't improve this breed.
その結果、彼はこの品種を改良しませんでした。
He is very evil
彼はとても邪悪です
Hard to say
言いにくい
what's the matter
どうしたの
my next topic
私の次のトピック
good very happy
とても幸せです
Let's listen to the principal
校長先生の話を聞いてみましょう
there are real scholars
本物の学者がいる
not like me fake
偽物の私とは違います
hehe
ふふふ
Hello Mr. Liu
こんにちは、劉さん
I am also researching
私も研究中です
food history
食の歴史
So I
それで私は
Because I think it's hard to be a food scientist
食品科学者になるのは難しいと思うから
become a historian
歴史家になる
It's hard to be a biologist
生物学者になるのは難しい
but i feel teacher
でも先生の気持ちはある
can put both
両方入れることができます
ken bai together
ケンバイ一緒に
I think I have gained a lot
たくさん得したと思います
Then I think what the teacher said today
それで、今日先生が言ったことを思うと、
mainly to say
主に言うこと
this
これ
columbus food
コロンブスの食べ物
some in Taiwan
台湾の一部
More Biological Effects
さらなる生物学的影響
nutritional impact
栄養への影響
This way I know there is a
このようにして、あることがわかります
John Hopkins teacher called
ジョン・ホプキンス先生から電話がありました
Cedrin Mines
セドリン鉱山
he studies sugar
他研究糖
Sugar, sugar can
砂糖、砂糖缶
with this sweetness
この甘さで
in the caribbean
カリブ海で
in Western Africa
西アフリカでは
with that british
あのイギリス人と
He combines this Triangle
彼はこの三角形を組み合わせます
U.K.
イギリス。
then raised the sugar
それから砂糖を上げました
A special place in modern history
現代史における特別な場所
Then I think the teacher means
そうすると、先生が言いたいのは、
of these countries
これらの国の
It is the food brought to Asia by the ministries of various countries
各国の省庁からアジアに持ち込まれた食べ物です
Is it possible for us to say
言えるでしょうか？
if further discussion
さらに議論があれば
Is it possible to discuss culturally
文化的な議論は可能ですか
special
比較特殊的
That is to say, there are
つまり、
Of course it doesn't have to be like Hitler
もちろんヒトラーのようにである必要はない
like sugar
砂糖のように
concrete things
具体的なもの
caused the final
決勝戦を引き起こした
Novelties of the Industrial Revolution
産業革命の新しさ
But the teacher's research
しかし、先生の研究では、
In terms of culture, does the teacher feel that
文化に関して、先生は次のように感じていますか?
these foods
これらの食べ物
Is there anything about something in Taiwan
台湾で何かある？
Exotic food in these five hundred years
この500年間のエキゾチックな食べ物
is there anything special
何か特別なことはありますか
Influence on culture
文化への影響
Thanks
ありがとう
The sweetest question is also quite interesting
この甘い質問も非常に興味深いです
Well what I just said is very simple
さて、私が今言ったことは非常に単純です
also a lot of this
これもたくさん
Of course the path is from the world
もちろん道は世界から
the whole world
全世界
next to become a problem
次に問題になるのは
is imperialism
帝国主義です
related to imperialism
帝国主義に関連した
Governing the sugar industry is imperialism
砂糖産業の統治は帝国主義である
because of the sugar industry
砂糖産業のせいで
Because it requires a lot of low-cost labor
低コストの人件費を大量に必要とするため、
This can only be done with nationalism
これはナショナリズムがあってこそできることだ
For example, India still uses very
たとえば、インドでは今でも非常に多くの
Tip-Level's coming to fight against Taiwan used to be
ティップレベルが台湾と戦うために来るのは以前は
so so
まあまあ
this
これ
Of course, Wang Huyu often knows here
もちろん、王胡宇はよくここを知っています
Dutch dry residue is mainly found in
オランダの乾燥残留物は主に次の場所で見つかります。
Pepper tiles are also planted
ペッパータイルも植えられています
Other crabs have also started to grow
他のカニも成長し始めています
This is what some people say is for resistance
これは抵抗のためだと言う人もいます
Resist selling too much coffee and tea
コーヒーや紅茶の過剰な販売を控える
so they use
だから彼らは使う
Use this to make up for it
これを使って補ってください
did not lose
負けなかった
Because why the Netherlands also has this plant sugar
なぜオランダにもこの植物性砂糖があるのか
I will try my best to do it
頑張ってやってみます
it dutch has had little success with coffee
オランダ人はコーヒーでほとんど成功していない
Didn't have much success with tea either
お茶でもあまり成功しなかった
So I had no choice but to develop towards this roasted sugar
だからこのローストシュガーを目指して開発するしかなかった
So Zhitang in Taiwan is actually
台湾のZhitangは実際には
Mostly based on the Dutch sugar industry
主にオランダの砂糖産業に基づいています
there are still problems
まだ問題があります
In fact, we have always wanted to say
実は私たちはずっと言いたかったのです
Don't forget Yabuy when the Dutch were in gay Taiwan
オランダ人がゲイの台湾にいた頃のヤブイを忘れるな
In fact, it also manages a place called Yagamaga
実はヤガマガという場所も運営しています。
But we often go that way, I think
でも、私たちはよくそういう方向に行ってしまうのだと思います
Too much reliance on the route of the so-called East India Company
いわゆる東インド会社のルートに依存しすぎている
That is to say, we are too dependent on
つまり、私たちは依存しすぎているのです。
We rely too much on this so-called discourse
私たちはこのいわゆる言説に頼りすぎています
Actually, I think it's a little bit wrong
実はそれはちょっと間違っていると思うんです
I don't understand that
それはわかりません
Why things must come from India
なぜインドから来たものでなければならないのか
dug from the claws
爪から掘り出された
Because he manages two colonies at the same time
彼は同時に 2 つのコロニーを管理しているため、
he can also from
彼はからも得ることができます
amaica
アマイカ
Because we don't have the Amaica way of thinking
私たちはアマイカの考え方を持っていないからです
don't forget the one in amaica
アマイカのことを忘れないでください
the so-called that
いわゆるそれ
Hugo is famous
ヒューゴは有名だよ
what else is he famous for
彼は他に何で有名ですか
His tobacco is also famous
彼のタバコも有名です
That means he
つまり、彼は
East India Company he came back from Amaica
東インド会社 彼はアマイカから帰ってきた
When he went around in a circle, he took this so-called
彼が円を描いて回ったとき、彼はいわゆるこれを手に取りました
This, this, I speak Spanish
これ、これ、私はスペイン語を話します
He also brought Spanish goods to Taiwan
スペイン製品も台湾に持ち込んだ
So I think this if explained in this way
このように説明するとこうなると思います
Would you be more inclined to say that?
もっとそう言いたいですか？
It seems that 7-11 wants to distribute goods, you know
セブンイレブンはグッズを配布したいらしいですよ
He is from Southern PU
彼は南部PU出身です
Then there is him in the north and HP
それから北とHPに彼がいます
Then I think with such a principle
では、このような原理を使って考えてみます
to explain the path of propagation
伝播経路を説明する
will it replace say
それは言うことを置き換えますか
If the Henan East India Company from Java or from India
ジャワまたはインドの河南東インド会社の場合
I think if the East India system at that time is included
当時の東インド体制も含めると思う
Will the history of this practice make another
この慣行の歴史が新たな歴史を生むだろうか
One by one one by one New interpretation
ひとつひとつ ひとつひとつ 新しい解釈
Of course, I'm talking about the more out-of-the-box one.
もちろん、私が話しているのは、より独創的なものについてです。
statement
声明
Then many scholars here can correct me
そうすれば、ここにいる多くの学者が私を正してくれるでしょう
But what?
でも何？
You also know the 7-11
セブンイレブンもご存知ですか？
from where
どこから
7-11 in Taiwan is from Japan
台湾のセブンイレブンは日本から来た
Where did Japan's 7-11 come from?
日本のセブンイレブンはどこから来たのでしょうか？
come from america
アメリカから来た
So how do you explain this?
それで、これをどう説明しますか？
is also very difficult to explain
これも説明するのが非常に難しいです
What about the way something spreads?
何かが広がる方法についてはどうですか？
As I said just now, it's not that simple
先ほども言いましたが、そんなに単純ではありません
So, for example, where does the population of Japan come from?
では、例えば日本の人口はどこから来たのでしょうか?
not from a certain country
特定の国の人ではない
Taiwanese
台湾人
So of course what I'm talking about today is just a few examples
もちろん、今日私が話していることはほんの一例です
i'm dead i'm not an expert
私は死んでいます、私は専門家ではありません
i just love food
私はただ食べ物が大好きです
So I can't argue with you what is the fact of the example
したがって、例の事実が何であるかについては議論できません
I used to give you the ability to stimulate your imagination
私はあなたに想像力を刺激する能力を与えていました
I will be very satisfied if I stimulate your interest
あなたの興味を刺激できれば、私はとても満足します
Where
どこ
you just said wood
今木って言ったよね
Wood
木
Subterranean Continents of the World
世界の地下大陸
he said
彼は言った
So what are the first and second largest crops?
それでは、1位と2位に多い作物は何でしょうか？
This is also the definition
これも定義です
then wheat rice
それから麦米
Does corn count as the third
トウモロコシは3番目に数えられますか
this is trainable
これは訓練可能です
So the most important thing is wheat and rice
だから一番大切なのは小麦と米だ
then uncle and corn
それからおじさんとトウモロコシ
it's hard to say
言うのが難しい
sometimes you crop
時々あなたはトリミングします
if you grow corn
トウモロコシを育てるなら
make it alcohol
アルコールにする
if you come to feed the car
車に餌をあげに来たら
Is it counted as food?
食品としてカウントされますか？
even if it's fake
たとえそれが偽物だったとしても
two questions
2つの質問
the first is
一つ目は
How did you research this food
この食べ物をどうやって調べたのか
I didn't say it before
前には言ってなかったけど
i gave out seven food
七品作りました
A biochemist studies Chinese things
生化学者は中国のものを研究しています
It has a lot to do with this master
このマスターと大きく関係がある
And I am directly motivated
そして私は直接的な動機を持っています
I'm going to South America
南米へ行きます
When going to South America at the same time
同時に南米に行く場合
See in person knuckle corn and more
ナックルコーンなどを直接見る
that's a direct deed
それは直接行為です
on the other hand
一方で
I'm not a research practitioner
私は研究者ではありません
Experts who also study practice here
実践を学ぶ専門家もここで
as far as the 16th century
16世紀まで
Many places in China refer to
中国の多くの場所では、
are starting to appear
現れ始めています
mentioned these things
これらのことについて言及しました
And they are all treated as new crops
そしてそれらはすべて新しい作物として扱われます
inside the reporter
記者の中では
So it's always a matter of peace
それで平和になった
just wrote an article
たった今記事を書きました
called "16th Century"
「16世紀」と呼ばれる
"15 Classics"
「15のクラシック」
including years in the mainland
本土での年月も含めて
Multiple ranks
複数のランク
Later there were some recordings
その後、いくつかの録音がありました
that is
あれは
Just now because it seems that the one
たった今そのような気がするので
keep mentioning
言及し続ける
just mentioned how to pass it on
それを渡す方法について述べたばかりです
is it possible
出来ますか
One of them came from China
そのうちの1人は中国から来ました
This is Taiwan
ここは台湾です
since the 16th century
16世紀以来
Still in use in the 17th century
17世紀にも使われている
to the 18th century
18世紀まで
When it comes to Qianlong
乾隆といえば
also invited someone
また誰かを誘った
To promote the cultivation of sweet potatoes all over the country
全国でサツマイモ栽培を推進するために
Because I also grow in many places
私もいろんなところに生えてるから
The character experience is about
キャラクターエクスペリエンスは約
Sweet Potato Saves Many People
サツマイモは多くの人を救う
including saving some
一部を節約することも含めて
Because sweet potatoes are so easy
さつまいもは簡単なので
And because China's more
そして中国はもっとだから
more restrictive
より制限的な
Population has been inflating
人口はインフレしてきている
When many things cannot be planted
植えられないものがたくさんあるとき
Can't grow rice
米が育てられない
are planted in the sand
砂の中に植えられています
or hills of hills
あるいは丘の中の丘
Those are the fish that rely on these peanuts
彼らはこれらの落花生魚に依存しています
sweet potato and so on
サツマイモなど
When there was no land for growing rice
米を作る土地がなかった時代
can feed many people
多くの人に食べさせることができる
and it's harvested very wide
そしてそれは非常に広範囲で収穫されます
So this promotion is
そこで今回のプロモーションは、
not temporary
一時的ではない
Doesn't seem like a source either
ソースもないようです
been promoting
推進してきた
sweet potato is a very good
サツマイモはとても良いです
until the time of channon
シャノンの時まで
there is also a registration station
登録ステーションもあります
sent someone everywhere to promote
プロモーションのためにどこにでも人を派遣する
promotion sometimes he still has one level left
昇格時にはまだレベルが 1 つ残っていることがある
So this thing originated
それでこのことは始まった
can be quite early
かなり早い時期になる可能性があります
And there can be many sources
そして、ソースはたくさんある可能性があります
and in fact it's not
そして実際にはそうではありません
stop all at once
一気に止めて
but in fact has been
しかし実際にはそうでした
You see, from the 16th century to the 18th century
16世紀から18世紀にかけて
And record things like overthrowing the book
そして本をひっくり返すなどのことを記録します
So it's not like Hua Shengmin's first record
つまり、華盛民の最初のレコードとは異なります
Alive Asan, a Portuguese
生きているアサン、ポルトガル人
He is like a Chongqing in the civil war
彼は内戦時の重慶人のようなものだ
He seems to be the first time that Huasheng Democracy enters China
華盛民主が中国に進出するのは彼が初めてのようだ
But it was still there until later
しかし、それは後までまだ存在していました
And the source is not one
そしてソースは一つではない
so what i mean is
だから私が言いたいのは
Seems like everything should be done
すべてをやるべきだと思われる
Or Taiwan or East Asia has some of the most exhausting resources from Central America
あるいは台湾や東アジアには中米からの最も枯渇する資源がある。
Possibly also from China
おそらく中国からも
Not necessarily an autonomous introduction to Manila or something
必ずしもマニラなどへの自主的な紹介ではありません
Yes I have a picture that is
はい、私はその写真を持っています
This arrow goes to many places
この矢は色々なところへ飛んでいきます
But this is also a question of quantity
しかし、これは量の問題でもあります
So you said the amount from China
中国からの金額を言ったわけですね
What is the amount following through Manila
マニラ経由の金額はいくらですか
if say or even talk
言うか話せば
This is where it comes from
ここから来ています
you can give three four five
3 4 5 を与えることができます
to say this
これを言うこと
maybe three or four hours
たぶん3時間か4時間
and i didn't say it
そして私はそれを言いませんでした
i can't talk that much
そんなに話せない
I just wanted to add to that
それに付け加えたかっただけです
friend's opinion
友人の意見
I think we're talking about a
について話していると思います
origin of species
種の起源
means to believe in that species
その種を信じるという意味です
Where does the special compared to the original come from?
オリジナルと比較した特別感はどこから来るのでしょうか？
Then we come from this thing
それから私たちはこのことから来ます
found that
あれを見つけた
how it spread
どのように広まったのか
The last one you mentioned just now has
あなたが今言及した最後のものは、
I think that's what I agree with
それは私も同意するところだと思います
That is to say, the path of this possibility is very different.
つまり、この可能性の道筋は大きく異なります。
For example, the academician just talked about the spread of water birds
たとえば、学者は先ほど水鳥の普及について話しました。
spread with ducks
アヒルで広がる
As for returning to species, where is
種への回帰はどこにあるのか
would i think this is not a
これはないと思いますか？
We learn from the spiritual law of spiritual love
私たちは霊的な愛の霊的な法則から学びます
go find that answer
その答えを見つけに行きましょう
Will it always form a situation of different opinions and different styles with Chinese culture?
中国文化とは常に異なる意見や異なるスタイルの状況を形成するのでしょうか？
I think today is a comparison
今日は比較だと思います
I personally research this rather headache problem
私は個人的にこのかなり頭の痛い問題を研究しています
Just came across the Egyptian texts
エジプトのテキストに出会った
Or something like that in Turkish literature
あるいはトルコ文学におけるそのようなもの
But how do we face this theory of origin?
しかし、私たちはこの起源理論にどう立ち向かうのでしょうか？
This I ask the academician is a scientist
これは学者に尋ねますが科学者です
That is, where did the species originate from?
つまり、その種はどこから来たのか？
Can you tell me for sure how much you just said is decided
今言ったどのくらいが決まっているのか、はっきり教えていただけますか？
Diversity determines the origin of that species
多様性がその種の起源を決定する
If so
もしそうなら
Does the area also determine the number of species?
地域によって種の数も決まるのでしょうか？
so to speak
いわば
Is it possible that it could happen elsewhere
他の場所でも起こる可能性はあるのか
Thanks
ありがとう
this is also possible
これも可能です
So often it turns out that
非常に多くの場合、次のことが判明します
where is the origin of human
人間の起源はどこにあるのか
Currently considered African
現在アフリカ人とみなされている
Russi is one, it's based on DNA
Russi はその 1 つです、それは DNA に基づいています
If you look at it in other ways in the future
今後別の観点から見てみると
not necessarily that
必ずしもそうではない
But now the DNA evidence is very strong
しかし現在、DNAの証拠は非常に強力です
For example, recent reports say
たとえば、最近の報道によれば、
Polaber
北極雄Polaber
where does it come from
それはどこから来たのですか
it's from aylan
アイランからです
Hui Xiong came
ホイ・シオンが来た
And it was a female female bear
そしてそれはメスのメスクマでした
This is based on DNA evidence
これはDNA証拠に基づいています
is so
そうだね
what about this species
この種はどうですか
So what about species?
では、種についてはどうでしょうか？
The question comes immediately, what is called seed
すぐに問題になるのは、シードと呼ばれるものです。
In the past, they were able to mate with each other, and vice versa.
過去には、彼らは互いに交尾することができ、その逆も同様でした。
But now this view has also become very complicated
しかし今ではこの見方も非常に複雑になっています
so it can't be simple
だから単純ではありえない
Then you can judge where this came from. It’s so simple.
そうすれば、これがどこから来たのかを判断できます。それはとても簡単です。
What I just said is that Japan’s ethnicity comes from many sources.
私が今言ったのは、日本の民族性はさまざまな源から来ているということです。
He can talk about the Japanese nation from the outside if he talks about it from the past.
過去のことを語れば、外から日本国家を語ることもできる。
i ask a final question
最後に質問します
I like food very much
私は食べ物がとても好きです
Then I came here today and saw that many of the things written in it are what I like to eat
そして今日ここに来て、そこに書かれているものの多くが私が食べたいものであることに気づきました
But unfortunately after listening to your talk, I found out that these things are all alien species
でも、残念なことに、あなたの話を聞いて、これらのものはすべて外来種であることがわかりました。
so maybe
かもね
After listening to today, I will probably go back to find something that is native to Taiwan.
今日これを聴いて帰ったら、台湾原産の曲を探しているかもしれません。
Because if they all eat exotic species, it means that I am also a foreigner.
彼らが外来種を食べるということは、私も外国人ということになるからです。
This is the first point
これが最初のポイントです
second point
2点目
Just now the academician mentioned something that I think is very important to everyone
今、学者が私が誰にとっても非常に重要だと思うことについて言及しました
Because you are important in life
あなたは人生においてとても大切な人だから
That is to say, I just mentioned that the white chocolate cannot be eaten.
つまり、先ほどホワイトチョコレートは食べられないと言いました。
Also not good
それも良くない
but a lot of yours like to eat dark chocolate
でも、あなたの多くはダークチョコレートが好きです
But it also mentioned that sugar is poisonous
しかし、砂糖には毒があるとも述べられていました
Does that chocolate have sugar in it?
そのチョコレートには砂糖が入っていますか？
So how many pills can they eat?
それで、彼らは何錠食べることができますか？
is it ok
大丈夫ですか
Because my wife likes chocolate very much
妻がチョコレートが大好きなので
So I have to limit the amount of it
だから量を制限する必要がある
so there will be no problem
だから問題ないでしょう
no white chocolate
ホワイトチョコレートはありません
If it is black, let it eat as much as possible
黒い場合はできるだけ食べさせてください。
eat less white
白人を食べる量を減らす
This is mine
これは私のものです
But of course you tell people not to smoke
でももちろん、あなたは人々にタバコを吸わないように言います
People still smoke
人々はまだ喫煙しています
So you tell people not to eat white chocolate
それであなたは人々にホワイトチョコレートを食べないように言います
People still eat
人々はまだ食べています
Of course, you'll be more at ease after you get married.
もちろん結婚したらもっと安心しますよ。
It seems that there is another hand raised
他にも手を挙げているようです
The humorous questions asked by the two groups
2つのグループからのユーモアあふれる質問
I'm asking a less humorous question
あまりユーモアのない質問をしています
That seems to be a lot of people recently
最近そういう人が多い気がする
In particular, Dean Li is very worried that the population is expanding so fast
特にリー学部長は人口がこれほど急速に拡大していることを非常に懸念している
Food will be a problem in the future
将来的には食料が問題になる
From Academician Li's point of view
李学士の視点から
what kind of food
どのような食べ物ですか
It is the most likely solution to our human feeding problem
それは人類の食糧問題に対する最も可能性の高い解決策です
this is a problem
これは問題だ
Another question is
もう一つの質問は、
It is also a relatively big problem
それは比較的大きな問題でもあります
Biofuel is a problem
バイオ燃料が問題になっている
I've been discussing issues now
私は今問題について話し合っています
so-called ground personnel
所謂的地色人員
those foods
それらの食べ物
not necessarily food
必ずしも食べ物ではない
just these foods
これらの食べ物だけ
Which one academician Li thinks is the most likely
李学者は誰が最も可能性が高いと考えていますか
Is there any hope that this will help people out
これが人々を助けるという希望はありますか
this person's problem
この人の問題
Nor does it depend on Nucleic energy
原子力エネルギーにも依存しない
or other such
またはその他の
if let me solve it
解決させていただければ
I think reducing the population is the only way
人口を減らすしか方法はないと思う
this is hard to do
これは難しいです
But you can count
でも数えることはできるよ
There are limits to using the biological revolution to produce food
生物革命を利用した食料生産には限界がある
Earth's sunlight is limited Earth's yang energy is limited
地球の太陽光は限られている 地球の陽エネルギーは限られている
So the earth's resources are limited
つまり地球の資源には限りがある
So we can't just use the so-called Green Revolution to solve it
したがって、いわゆる緑の革命だけでそれを解決することはできません。
And the so-called Biofield these so-called substitutes
そして、いわゆるバイオフィールド、これらのいわゆる代替品
For example, like using this hall to make alcohol for cars
例えば、このホールを使って車用のお酒を作るとか。
Of course it's a sacrifice, and it's also a sacrifice of this land.
もちろんそれは犠牲であり、この土地の犠牲でもあります。
Where you should grow food grow dryness
食物を育てるべき場所は乾燥した場所で育てる
you grow less food to eat
食べる食料が減ります
This can be solved in the short term
これは短期間で解決できる
long-term problem
長期的な問題
so i think
だから私は思う
Will this reduce the population is the only way
これが人口を減らす唯一の方法ですか
Maybe this society has offended many people
おそらくこの社会は多くの人を傷つけてきたでしょう
our last question
私たちの最後の質問
Thanks
ありがとう
A very wonderful speech by an academician today
今日の学者による非常に素晴らしいスピーチ
really learned a lot
本当にたくさんのことを学びました
So I'll take a more personal question
そこで、より個人的な質問をさせていただきます
To end today is a question and answer
今日は質疑応答で終わります
is your interest in food whether it is your personal interest
食べ物に興味がありますか? それは個人的な興味ですか?
Or academically, professionally
あるいは学術的、専門的に
so professional
とてもプロフェッショナル
Then I think Academician, do you have a set?
それから学者さん、セットはありますか？
It is a personal philosophy of this diet
これはこのダイエットの個人的な哲学です
Would you like to share with you
あなたと共有しませんか
The first one has already been mentioned
1つ目はすでに述べました
with white chocolate
ホワイトチョコレート入り
The second is
2つ目は
So it's better to eat less and not more
だから、食べる量を増やすのではなく、減らすほうが良いのです
This is the first one
これが最初のものです
not study
勉強しない
This is how it can be calculated
こうやって計算できるんですね
I just calculated the calorie requirement
必要カロリーを計算してみました
I can show you
お見せできます
Americans eat too much calorie
アメリカ人はカロリーを摂りすぎます
So should reduce
だから減らすべきだ
Because there are too many problems
問題が多すぎるから
and you put diabetes
そしてあなたは糖尿病になります
The so-called cost of medicine
いわゆる薬代
Considerable for the country as a whole
国全体としては相当な額
not only impressive but also terrible
印象的であるだけでなく恐ろしい
So I think I don't care about these two points.
ですので、この２点については気にならないと思います。
almost
ほとんど
Doctor Li is very good today
リー医師は今日もとても元気です
very humorous
とてもユーモラスな
so thank you all for coming today
今日は来てくれてありがとう
Thanks
ありがとう
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
redundant
冗長な